很久很久以前，在一個遙遠的銀河星系....
拉穆行星
- 媽媽 - 我們知道
- Mama! - We know.
琴 收拾東西 該走了
Jyn, gather your things. It's time.
- 喂 - 索 我是麗拉
- Hello? - Saw, it's Lyra.
出事了 他來抓我們了
It's happened. He's come for us.
按計劃行事
You know what to do.
琴 過來
Jyn, come here.
記住了 無論我做什麼
Remember, whatever I do,
都是為了保護你
I do it to protect you.
知道嗎
Say you understand.
我知道 爸爸
I understand.
我愛你 星塵
I love you, Stardust.
我也愛你 爸爸
I love you, too, Papa.
蓋倫
Galen.
走
Go.
琴
Jyn.
你認識路的
You know where to go, don't you?
要相信原力
Trust the Force.
找你可真不容易 蓋倫
You're a hard man to find, Galen.
當農民了
But farming...
何必呢 大材小用
Really? Man of your talents?
這兒的生活平靜
It's a peaceful life.
不過也很孤獨吧
It's lonely, I imagine.
麗拉去世了
Since Lyra died, yes.
節哀順變
My condolences.
搜查房子
Search the house.
你想要什麼
What is it you want?
工程停頓了 我需要你回來
The work has stalled. I need you to come back.
我不會答應的
I won't do it, Krennic.
我們站在歷史的轉折點
We were on the verge of greatness.
只差一小步
We were this close
就能奠定銀河系的和平與安定了 蓋倫
to providing peace and security for the galaxy.
那是恐怖 不是和平
You're confusing peace with terror.
好吧
Well,
萬事開頭難
you have to start somewhere.
我幫不了你 科倫尼克
I'd be of no help, Krennic.
我精力不如從前了
My mind just isn't what it was.
記憶力差不說
I have trouble remembering.
還總忘事
Even simple things.
蓋倫
Galen...
你才華過人 可撒謊技術太差
You're an inspired scientist, but you're a terrible liar.
雖然也很努力地想
Now, I admire the effort. I really do.
噢 看吶 麗拉死而復生了
Oh, look, here's Lyra, back from the dead.
太神奇了
It's a miracle.
站住
Stop!
噢 麗拉
Oh, Lyra,
你又來找我的麻煩了
troublesome as ever.
你別想帶走他
You're not taking him.
不 當然不 我帶你們一起走
No, of course I'm not. I'm taking you all.
全家人 你和孩子 去過好日子
You'll all come. You, your child. You'll all live in comfort.
做你的人質
As hostages.
我是 讓你們做帝國的英雄
As heroes of the Empire.
麗拉
Lyra.
放下槍
Put it down.
你想想清楚
Think very carefully.
- 你不會得逞的 - 動手
- You will never win. - Do it.
麗拉
Lyra!
他還有個孩子
They have a child!
找到她
Find it!
孩子
My child!
過來
Come.
來
我們還有很長的一段路要走呢
We have a long ride ahead of us.
俠盜一號
安全檢查
Check in security,
牢房4227
cell block 4227.
4227.
貿易前哨站
卡夫林環
TK-62 XX-25900
TK-62, XX-25900.
再不來我就要走了
I was about to leave.
我已經很快了
I came as fast as I could.
我必須回到船上 跟我走
I have to get back on board. Walk with me.
回傑達嗎
Back to Jedha?
他們不會等我的
They'll leave without me.
等等 你有傑達的消息
Easy! You have news from Jedha.
快說
Come on.
是這麼回事 有一個帝國貨船飛行員
An Imperial pilot, one of the cargo drivers
昨天叛逃了
he defected yesterday.
他說帝國在建造一種武器
He's telling people they're making a weapon.
凱伯水晶就用在這種武器上
The kyber crystals, that's what they're for.
什麼樣的武器
What kind of weapon?
我必須要走了
Look, I have to go.
是什麼樣的武器
What kind of weapon?
行星殺手
A planet killer!
這是他的原話
That's what he called it!
行星殺手
A planet killer?
一個叫厄索的人派他來
Someone named Erso sent him.
那個人是索的老朋友
Some old friend of Saw's.
蓋倫·厄索 是不是
Galen Erso? Was it?
我不知道 我們走的時候他們正在找索
I don't know! They were looking for Saw when we left.
還有誰知道這件事
Who else knows about this?
我真的不知道
I have no idea.
我們暴露了
It's all falling apart.
索說得對
Saw's right.
到處都是帝國的間諜
There's spies everywhere.
怎麼回事
What's all this?
把你們的掃瞄證件拿出來
Come on, let's see some scandocs.
好的 稍等 我手上沒拿
Yeah, of course. Just... My gloves.
不
No!
你幹什麼
What have you done?
士兵中彈 9區
Troopers down. Section 9.
你瘋了嗎
Are you crazy?
我的手受傷了 沒辦法爬出去了
I'll never climb out of here. My arm!
快讓開
Get out of the way.
快 快
Move! Move!
嗨 冷靜點兒 冷靜點兒
Hey. Calm down. Calm down.
不會有事的
It will be all right.
傑達
帝國佔領衛星
是他嗎
Is that him?
他看起來 跟我想像的不太一樣啊
He looks kind of different to how I imagined.
注意腳下
是飛行員... 那個叛逃者.
好吧 你是索·格瑞拉
Okay. So you're Saw Gerrera?
索·格瑞拉
Saw Gerrera?
不是
No?
我們這是在浪費時間
Okay, we're just wasting time that we don't have.
我必須見索·格瑞拉 我說了很多遍了
I need to speak to Saw Gerrera. I keep telling them.
不能再耽誤了
Before it's too late.
把頭低下
帝國士兵將會搜捕他...
我們在荒郊野外幹什麼
We're out here in the middle of nowhere.
我們 我們必須去傑達城裏
We need to get to Jedha City.
我有緊急情報 你們懂不懂
What part of "urgent message" do you guys not understand?
我是自己人
We are all on the same side.
你們別只看制服不看人吶
If you just see past the uniform for a minute.
沃巴尼
帝國勞改營
怎麼了
What now?
不知道 肯定是要再接人
I don't know. Must be another pickup.
我以為人都齊了
I thought we had everybody.
安全了 長官
All clear, sir.
哈利克 莉安娜·哈利克
Hallik! Liana Hallik!
是她
Her.
你想離開這兒嗎
You wanna get out of here?
嗨 帶上我
Hey! What about me?
給我鑰匙 給我鑰匙
Give me the keys! Give me the keys!
我要祝賀你 你被營救了
Congratulations. You are being rescued.
請你不要再抵抗
Please do not resist.
雅文四號
反抗軍聯盟總部
LU-28 到四層維修部報到
LU-28, report to maintenance level 4.
你自稱是叫什麼 莉安娜·哈利克
You're currently calling yourself Liana Hallik.
是這樣嗎
Is that correct?
私藏武器不說
Possession of unsanctioned weapons.
偽造帝國文書
Forgery of Imperial documents.
並且犯有故意傷害 潛逃
Aggravated assault. Escape from custody.
還有拒捕的罪行
Resisting arrest.
如果帝國當局知道你的真實身份
Imagine if the Imperial authorities had found out...
會怎麼樣 琴·厄索
who you really were, Jyn Erso.
這才是你的真實名字吧
That is your given name, is it not?
琴·厄索 父親是蓋倫·厄索
Jyn Erso, daughter of Galen Erso?
與帝國合作的武器研發專家
A known Imperial collaborator in weapons development.
你們想怎樣
What is this?
給你個重新開始的機會
It's a chance for you to make a fresh start.
你或許能幫助我們
We think you might be able to help us.
這位是卡西亞·安多上尉 義軍情報員
This is Captain Cassian Andor, Rebel Intelligence.
你上一次聯繫你父親是什麼時候
When was the last time you were in contact with your father?
十五年前了
15 years ago.
那你知道他這些年的行蹤嗎
Any idea where he's been all that time?
我寧可當他死了
I like to think he's dead.
那樣對我更好
Makes things easier.
為什麼這麼想
Easier than what?
免得他成為帝國戰爭的工具
That he's been a tool of the Imperial war machine?
我從來就對政治不感興趣
I've never had the luxury of political opinions.
真的
Really?
你上一次聯繫索·格瑞拉是什麼時候
When was your last contact with Saw Gerrera?
已經很久以前了
It's been a long time.
但是他卻記得你
But he'll remember you, though.
對嗎
Wouldn't he?
如果你去拜訪他 他可能會見你
He might agree to meet you, if you came as a friend.
時間不等讓人 如果你不說你從哪兒來
We're up against the clock here, girl, so if there's nothing to talk about,
我們就送你回哪兒去
we'll just put you back where we found you.
我小的時候索·格瑞拉救了我 把我養大
I was a child. Saw Gerrera saved my life. He raised me.
很多年沒有見了
But I have no idea where he is.
我不知道他在哪兒
I haven't seen him in years.
我們能找到他
We know how to find him.
這個不用擔心
That's not our problem.
我們現在需要的是
What we need is someone
有人把我們活著領進門
who gets us through the door without being killed.
你們不都是起義軍嗎
You're all rebels, aren't you?
是的 但索·格瑞拉是極端分子
Yes, but Saw Gerrera is an extremist.
他單打獨鬥 早就脫離了義軍同盟
He's been fighting on his own since he broke with the Rebellion.
他生性好戰
His militancy has caused the Alliance
已經為義軍同盟製造了很多麻煩
a great many problems.
我們現在沒有選擇 只能想辦法
We have no choice now but to try
和他重歸於好
and mend that broken trust.
這跟我父親有什麼關係吧
What does this have to do with my father?
有一名帝國飛行員叛逃了 在傑達
There's an Imperial defector in Jedha. A pilot.
落在了索·格瑞拉的手裏
He's been held by Saw Gerrera.
他說皇帝在建造一種武器
He's claiming the Emperor is creating a weapon
威力足以摧毀整個行星
with the power to destroy entire planets.
據飛行員說 是你父親派他來的
The pilot says he was sent by your father.
我們必須要在武器完工前摧毀它
We need to stop this weapon before it is finished.
安多上尉的任務 是證實飛行員的情報
Captain Andor's mission is to authenticate the pilot's story.
並盡可能找到你父親
And then, if possible, find your father.
你父親是研發這座超級武器的核心成員
It appears he is critical to the development of this super weapon.
鑒於事態嚴重
Given the gravity of the situation
而且你跟索也很熟悉
and your history with Saw,
我們希望索能幫助我們找到你父親
we're hoping that he will help us locate your father
讓他在參議院提供證詞
and return him to the Senate for testimony.
要是我答應呢
And if I do it?
我們會讓你重獲自由
We'll make sure you go free.
安多上尉
Captain Andor.
我是K-2SO
I'm K-2SO.
我是被重新編程的帝國機器人
I'm a reprogrammed Imperial droid.
我應該記得你
I remember you.
委員會指派你和我們一起去傑達
I see the Council is sending you with us to Jedha.
你說的沒錯
Apparently so.
這其實是個壞主意
That is a bad idea.
我知道 卡西亞也知道
I think so, and so does Cassian.
可我懂什麼
What do I know?
我只是一個戰略分析員
My specialty is just strategic analysis.
蓋倫是帝國武器項目的關鍵人物
Galen Erso is vital to the Empire's weapons program.
忘掉我剛才說的話
Forget what you heard in there.
沒有什麼營救計劃
There will be no extraction.
找到他
You find him...
殺了他
you kill him.
就地執行
Then and there.
穿梭機LMTR-20
Shuttle number LMTR-20.
準備起飛 正在檢查授權
Prepare for takeoff while we check your authorization.
見過K-2了
You met K-2?
很直接
Charming.
他的電子腦想到什麼就說什麼
He tends to say whatever comes into his circuits.
我看 是重新編程的副作用
It's a byproduct of the reprogram.
為什麼她有槍而我沒有
Why does she get a blaster and I don't?
- 什麼 - 我知道怎麼用槍
- What? - I know how to use it.
我怕的就是這個 把槍給我
That's what I'm afraid of. Give it to me.
我們要去傑達
We're going to Jedha.
那裏是戰區
That's a war zone.
這個不是重點 你從哪兒拿的
That's not the point. Where'd you get it?
我找的
I found it.
回答含糊其辭 難以信服
I find that answer vague and unconvincing.
信任是相互的
Trust goes both ways.
你允許她帶槍
You're letting her keep it?
你想不想知道
Would you like to know the probability
她朝你開槍的概率
of her using it against you?
很高
It's high.
我們走吧
Let's get going.
相當的高
It's very high.
m 211 -8 b 217 -6 217 -4 217 -2 l 217 24 b 217 26 217 29 211 31 l 31 31 b 26 29 26 26 26 24 l 26 -2 b 26 -4 26 -6 31 -8
m 38 11 b 41 11 45 11 49 11 b 48 15 48 19 48 22 b 45 22 41 22 38 22 b 38 19 38 15 38 11 m 118 93 b 121 93 125 93 128 93 b 128 96 128 99 128 104 b 125 104 121 104 117 104 b 118 99 118 96 118 93 m 129 23 b 125 23 122 23 118 23 b 118 19 118 16 118 13 b 122 13 125 13 129 13 b 129 16 129 20 129 23 m 51 88 b 51 87 51 86 51 85 b 53 85 54 85 55 85 b 55 86 55 87 55 88 b 54 88 53 88 51 88 m 66 103 b 66 101 66 100 66 99 b 67 99 68 99 69 99 b 69 100 69 102 69 103 b 68 103 67 103 66 103 m 62 95 b 64 95 65 95 66 95 b 66 97 66 98 66 99 b 65 99 64 99 62 99 b 62 98 62 97 62 95 m 111 45 b 111 44 111 42 111 41 b 111 41 112 41 114 41 b 114 42 114 44 114 45 b 112 45 112 45 111 45 m 96 74 b 96 73 96 71 96 70 b 96 70 98 70 99 70 b 99 71 99 73 99 74 b 98 74 97 74 96 74 m 88 99 b 87 99 85 99 84 99 b 84 101 84 102 84 103 b 83 103 82 103 81 103 b 81 102 81 101 81 99 b 80 99 79 99 77 99 b 77 98 77 97 77 95 b 76 95 74 95 73 95 b 73 94 73 93 73 92 b 76 92 79 92 81 92 b 81 93 81 94 81 95 b 83 95 85 95 88 95 b 88 97 88 98 88 99 m 85 56 b 84 56 83 56 81 56 b 81 55 81 53 81 52 b 83 52 83 52 85 52 b 85 53 85 55 85 56 m 114 67 b 113 67 112 67 110 67 b 110 68 110 70 110 71 b 108 71 106 71 103 70 b 103 69 103 68 103 67 b 104 67 105 67 106 67 b 106 66 106 64 106 63 b 105 63 104 63 103 63 b 103 65 103 66 103 67 b 100 67 98 67 96 67 b 96 68 96 69 96 70 b 95 70 93 70 92 70 b 92 69 92 68 92 67 b 91 67 89 67 88 67 b 88 66 88 64 88 63 b 92 63 95 63 99 63 b 99 62 99 61 99 59 b 98 59 97 59 96 59 b 96 57 96 55 96 52 b 95 52 93 52 92 52 b 92 51 92 50 92 48 b 93 48 94 48 96 48 b 96 47 96 46 96 45 b 99 45 101 45 103 45 b 103 46 103 48 103 49 b 102 49 101 49 100 49 b 100 51 100 53 100 56 b 101 56 102 56 103 56 b 103 53 103 51 103 49 b 104 49 106 49 107 49 b 107 48 107 46 107 45 b 108 45 110 45 111 45 b 111 47 111 48 111 49 b 112 49 112 49 114 49 b 114 50 114 51 114 52 b 113 52 112 52 111 52 b 111 53 111 55 111 56 b 113 56 115 56 118 56 b 118 59 118 61 118 63 b 117 63 115 63 114 63 b 114 62 114 61 114 60 b 112 60 112 60 111 60 b 111 61 111 62 111 63 b 112 63 113 63 114 63 b 114 64 114 66 114 67 m 33 106 b 33 107 33 108 33 110 b 32 110 31 110 29 110 b 30 108 30 107 30 106 b 31 106 31 106 33 106 m 33 99 b 33 100 33 101 33 102 b 32 102 31 102 30 102 b 30 101 30 100 30 99 b 31 99 32 99 33 99 m 37 95 b 36 97 36 98 36 99 b 35 99 34 99 33 99 l 33 99 b 33 98 33 96 33 95 l 33 95 b 34 95 35 95 37 95 m 37 80 b 37 79 37 79 37 77 b 38 77 39 77 41 77 b 41 78 41 79 41 80 l 41 80 b 39 80 38 80 37 80 m 38 37 b 38 36 38 35 38 33 b 39 33 39 33 41 33 b 41 34 41 36 41 37 b 39 37 39 37 38 37 b 38 37 38 37 38 37 m 45 74 b 43 74 42 74 41 74 b 41 72 41 71 41 70 b 41 70 41 70 41 70 b 42 70 43 70 45 70 l 45 70 b 45 71 45 72 45 74 m 41 48 b 41 47 41 46 41 44 b 42 44 43 44 45 44 b 44 45 44 47 44 48 b 43 48 42 48 41 48 b 41 48 41 48 41 48 m 49 37 b 49 38 49 40 49 41 b 47 41 46 41 45 41 b 45 40 45 38 45 37 b 46 37 47 37 49 37 b 49 37 49 37 49 37 m 52 55 b 51 55 50 55 48 55 b 48 54 48 53 48 52 b 50 52 51 52 52 52 l 52 52 b 52 53 52 54 52 55 m 89 5 b 91 5 92 5 92 5 b 92 6 92 7 92 9 b 92 9 90 9 89 9 b 89 7 89 6 89 5 m 33 95 b 32 95 31 95 30 95 b 30 93 30 90 30 88 b 31 88 32 88 33 88 l 33 88 b 33 90 33 93 33 95 m 37 63 b 35 63 32 63 30 62 b 30 61 30 60 30 59 b 32 59 35 59 37 59 b 37 59 37 59 37 59 b 37 60 37 61 37 63 b 37 63 37 63 37 63 m 38 37 b 38 38 38 40 38 41 b 35 41 32 41 30 41 b 30 40 30 38 30 37 b 32 37 35 37 38 37 m 96 12 b 96 10 96 8 96 5 b 98 5 99 5 100 5 b 100 7 100 10 100 12 l 100 12 b 99 12 98 12 96 12 m 93 19 b 93 17 93 15 93 12 b 94 12 95 12 96 12 l 96 12 b 96 15 96 17 96 19 l 96 19 b 95 19 94 19 93 19 m 110 78 b 112 78 115 78 117 78 b 117 79 117 80 117 82 b 115 82 112 82 110 82 b 110 80 110 79 110 78 b 110 78 110 78 110 78 m 133 60 b 133 60 134 60 136 60 b 136 62 136 65 136 67 b 134 67 134 67 133 67 l 133 67 b 133 65 133 62 133 60 m 33 88 b 33 87 33 86 33 84 b 32 84 31 84 30 84 b 30 83 30 82 30 80 b 32 80 35 80 37 80 l 37 80 b 37 83 37 86 37 88 l 37 88 b 36 88 34 88 33 88 m 43 106 b 42 106 42 106 41 106 b 41 108 41 109 41 110 b 39 110 38 110 36 110 b 36 107 36 105 36 102 b 39 102 41 102 43 102 b 43 104 43 105 43 106 m 55 106 b 55 108 55 109 55 110 b 53 110 50 110 47 110 b 47 108 47 105 47 102 b 49 102 50 102 51 102 l 51 102 b 51 104 51 105 51 106 b 53 106 54 106 55 106 m 60 37 b 55 37 52 37 49 37 l 49 37 b 49 36 49 34 49 33 b 52 33 55 33 60 34 b 60 35 60 36 60 37 b 60 37 60 37 60 37 m 100 12 b 102 12 104 13 107 13 b 107 14 107 15 107 16 b 106 16 105 16 104 16 b 104 17 104 18 104 19 b 102 19 101 19 100 19 l 100 19 b 100 17 100 15 100 12 m 37 48 b 36 48 35 48 34 48 b 34 51 34 53 34 55 b 32 55 31 55 30 55 b 30 52 30 48 30 44 b 32 44 35 44 37 44 b 37 45 37 47 37 48 m 37 59 b 37 55 37 52 37 48 l 37 48 b 39 48 40 48 41 48 l 41 48 b 41 51 41 53 41 55 b 42 55 43 55 44 55 b 44 56 44 57 44 59 b 42 59 39 59 37 59 b 37 59 37 59 37 59 m 121 71 b 121 72 121 73 121 74 b 118 74 114 74 110 74 l 110 74 b 110 73 110 72 110 71 b 112 71 113 71 114 71 b 114 70 114 68 114 67 b 115 67 116 67 118 67 b 118 68 118 70 118 71 b 119 71 120 71 121 71 m 37 63 b 38 63 39 63 41 63 b 41 65 41 67 41 70 b 41 70 41 70 41 70 b 39 70 38 70 37 70 b 37 71 37 72 37 74 b 35 73 32 73 30 73 b 30 72 30 71 30 70 b 31 70 32 70 34 70 b 34 68 34 67 34 66 b 35 66 35 66 37 66 b 37 65 37 64 37 63 m 70 37 b 73 37 75 37 78 37 l 78 37 b 78 38 78 40 78 41 b 76 41 75 41 74 41 b 74 42 74 44 74 45 b 75 45 76 45 77 45 b 77 46 77 47 77 48 b 75 48 72 48 70 48 l 70 48 b 70 45 70 41 70 37 m 111 38 b 111 37 111 36 111 34 b 118 34 125 34 133 34 b 133 36 133 37 133 38 l 133 38 b 125 38 118 38 111 38 m 129 49 b 129 50 129 51 129 52 b 130 52 131 52 133 52 b 133 55 133 57 133 60 l 133 60 b 129 60 125 60 122 60 b 122 59 122 57 122 56 b 123 56 124 56 125 56 b 125 53 125 51 125 49 l 125 49 b 126 49 128 49 129 49 m 133 38 b 134 38 135 38 136 38 b 136 41 136 43 136 45 b 135 45 134 45 133 45 b 133 47 133 48 133 49 b 131 49 130 49 129 49 l 129 49 b 129 48 129 47 129 45 b 127 45 126 45 125 45 b 125 47 125 48 125 49 l 125 49 b 123 49 121 49 118 49 b 118 48 118 47 118 45 b 119 45 121 45 121 45 b 122 44 122 42 122 41 b 125 41 129 41 133 42 b 133 40 133 39 133 38 m 133 74 b 133 74 134 74 136 74 b 136 77 136 79 136 82 b 132 82 129 82 125 82 b 125 78 125 74 125 71 b 124 71 123 71 121 71 l 121 71 b 122 68 122 66 122 63 b 124 63 126 63 129 63 b 129 64 129 66 129 67 b 130 67 131 67 133 67 l 133 67 b 133 70 133 72 133 74 b 131 74 130 74 129 74 b 129 75 129 76 129 78 b 130 78 131 78 132 78 b 132 77 133 75 133 74 m 103 85 b 103 86 103 87 103 89 b 104 89 105 89 106 89 b 106 95 106 101 106 107 b 105 107 104 107 103 107 b 103 108 103 109 103 110 b 100 110 98 110 95 110 b 95 109 95 108 95 106 b 96 106 98 106 99 106 b 99 105 99 104 99 103 b 98 103 96 103 95 103 b 95 102 95 101 95 99 b 94 99 93 99 92 99 l 92 99 b 92 98 92 97 92 95 b 94 95 97 96 99 96 b 99 97 99 98 99 99 b 100 99 102 99 102 99 b 102 97 102 95 103 92 b 101 92 100 92 99 92 b 99 90 99 87 99 85 b 100 85 102 85 103 85 m 92 99 b 92 102 92 104 92 106 b 91 106 89 106 88 106 b 88 108 88 109 88 110 b 78 110 68 110 58 110 b 58 109 58 108 59 106 b 57 106 56 106 55 106 l 55 106 b 55 105 55 104 55 102 l 55 102 b 59 102 62 103 66 103 b 66 104 66 105 66 106 b 69 106 71 106 73 106 b 73 105 73 104 73 103 b 74 103 76 103 77 103 b 77 104 77 105 77 106 b 80 106 82 106 84 106 b 84 105 84 104 84 103 b 85 103 87 103 88 103 b 88 102 88 101 88 99 b 89 99 91 99 92 99 m 52 26 b 52 20 52 14 52 8 b 46 8 40 8 34 8 b 34 14 34 20 34 26 b 40 26 46 26 52 26 m 30 30 b 30 21 30 13 31 5 b 39 5 47 5 55 5 b 55 13 55 21 55 30 b 47 30 39 30 30 30 m 114 107 b 120 107 126 107 131 107 b 131 101 131 95 132 89 b 126 89 120 89 114 89 b 114 95 114 101 114 107 m 110 110 b 110 102 110 94 110 85 b 119 85 127 85 136 85 b 136 94 136 102 136 111 b 127 110 118 110 110 110 m 133 9 b 126 9 121 9 115 9 b 115 15 115 21 115 27 b 121 27 127 27 133 27 b 133 21 133 15 133 9 m 111 30 b 111 22 111 14 111 5 b 119 5 128 5 137 6 b 136 14 136 22 136 31 b 128 31 119 30 111 30 m 74 23 b 73 23 72 23 70 23 b 70 25 70 28 70 30 b 69 30 68 30 67 30 b 67 26 67 23 67 19 b 68 19 69 19 70 19 b 70 18 70 17 70 15 b 69 15 68 15 67 15 b 67 17 67 18 67 19 b 66 19 65 19 64 19 b 63 23 63 26 63 30 b 62 30 61 30 60 30 b 60 22 60 13 60 5 b 61 5 62 5 64 5 b 64 7 64 10 64 12 b 65 12 65 12 66 12 b 66 10 66 7 66 5 b 68 5 69 5 71 5 b 71 6 71 7 70 9 b 73 9 75 9 78 9 b 78 7 78 6 78 5 b 79 5 81 5 82 5 b 82 6 82 7 82 9 b 83 9 84 9 85 9 b 85 10 85 11 85 12 b 87 12 87 12 89 12 b 89 13 89 14 88 16 b 85 15 81 15 78 15 b 78 14 78 13 78 12 b 76 12 76 12 74 12 b 74 13 74 14 74 15 b 76 15 77 15 78 15 b 78 17 78 18 78 19 b 77 19 76 19 74 19 b 74 21 74 22 74 23 m 48 91 b 51 91 55 91 58 91 b 58 88 58 85 58 81 b 55 80 51 80 48 80 b 48 85 48 88 48 91 m 41 80 b 42 80 43 80 45 80 b 45 78 45 76 45 74 l 45 74 b 46 74 47 74 48 74 l 48 74 b 48 75 48 76 48 77 b 51 77 55 77 59 77 b 59 75 59 72 59 70 b 60 70 61 70 63 70 l 63 70 b 63 74 62 77 62 81 b 64 81 65 81 66 81 b 66 83 66 86 66 88 b 69 88 71 88 73 88 l 73 88 b 73 90 73 91 73 92 b 72 92 71 92 70 92 b 70 93 70 94 70 95 b 68 95 67 95 66 95 b 66 94 66 93 66 92 b 65 92 64 92 62 92 b 62 93 62 94 62 95 b 61 95 60 95 59 95 b 59 97 59 98 59 99 b 57 99 56 99 55 99 b 55 101 55 101 55 102 l 55 102 b 54 102 53 102 51 102 l 51 102 b 51 101 51 100 51 99 b 50 99 49 99 48 99 b 48 98 48 97 48 95 b 46 95 45 95 44 95 b 44 97 44 98 44 99 b 43 99 42 99 41 99 b 41 98 41 97 41 95 b 39 95 38 95 37 95 l 37 95 b 37 93 37 90 37 88 l 37 88 b 39 88 41 88 44 88 b 44 87 44 86 44 85 b 43 85 42 85 41 85 b 41 83 41 82 41 80 m 85 26 b 85 28 85 29 85 30 b 87 30 88 30 88 30 b 88 29 88 28 88 26 b 88 26 87 26 85 26 m 85 41 b 86 41 88 41 88 41 b 88 38 88 36 88 34 b 87 34 87 34 85 34 b 85 36 85 38 85 41 m 100 19 b 100 23 100 27 100 30 b 101 30 102 30 103 30 b 103 28 103 26 104 23 b 105 23 106 23 107 23 b 107 28 107 33 107 38 b 108 38 110 38 111 38 l 111 38 b 111 39 111 40 111 41 b 110 41 108 41 107 41 b 107 42 107 44 107 45 b 106 45 104 45 103 45 b 103 44 103 42 103 41 b 102 41 101 41 100 41 b 100 40 100 39 100 38 b 101 38 102 38 103 38 b 103 37 103 35 103 34 b 102 34 101 34 100 34 b 100 36 100 37 100 38 b 98 38 95 38 92 37 b 92 40 92 42 92 45 b 89 45 88 45 85 45 b 85 46 85 47 85 48 b 83 48 83 48 81 48 b 81 45 81 41 81 37 b 80 37 79 37 78 37 l 78 37 b 78 36 78 36 78 34 b 77 34 76 34 74 34 b 74 30 74 26 74 23 l 74 23 b 75 23 76 23 78 23 b 78 25 78 28 78 30 b 79 30 80 30 81 30 b 81 28 81 25 81 23 b 83 23 84 23 85 23 b 85 22 85 21 85 19 b 88 19 90 19 93 19 l 93 19 b 92 23 92 27 92 30 b 93 30 95 30 96 30 b 96 27 96 23 96 19 l 96 19 b 98 19 99 19 100 19 m 85 81 b 85 82 85 83 85 85 b 86 85 87 85 88 85 b 88 83 88 82 88 81 b 87 81 86 81 85 81 m 110 78 b 109 78 108 78 107 78 b 107 80 107 83 107 85 b 105 85 104 85 103 85 l 103 85 b 103 84 103 83 103 81 b 100 81 98 81 95 81 b 95 83 95 86 95 89 b 94 89 93 89 92 89 b 92 90 92 91 92 92 b 90 92 89 92 88 92 b 88 91 88 90 88 89 b 87 89 86 89 84 89 b 84 90 84 91 84 92 b 83 92 81 92 81 92 b 81 91 81 90 81 89 b 78 89 76 89 73 88 l 73 88 b 73 86 73 83 73 81 b 75 81 76 81 77 81 b 77 82 77 83 77 85 b 79 85 80 85 80 85 b 80 83 80 82 81 81 b 79 81 78 81 77 81 b 77 76 77 71 77 67 b 79 67 80 67 81 67 b 81 66 81 64 81 63 b 80 63 79 63 77 63 b 77 64 77 66 77 67 b 76 67 75 67 74 67 l 74 67 b 74 64 74 61 74 59 l 74 59 b 77 59 81 59 85 59 b 85 58 85 57 85 56 l 85 56 b 87 56 89 56 92 56 b 92 57 92 58 92 59 b 91 59 89 59 88 59 b 88 61 88 61 88 63 b 87 63 86 63 85 63 b 85 66 85 68 85 70 b 86 70 87 70 88 70 b 88 72 88 75 88 78 b 89 78 91 78 92 78 b 92 76 92 75 92 74 b 93 74 95 74 96 74 b 96 75 96 76 96 78 b 98 78 100 78 103 78 b 103 76 103 75 103 74 b 106 74 108 74 110 74 l 110 74 b 110 75 110 76 110 78 m 45 70 b 45 67 45 66 45 63 b 47 63 49 63 52 63 b 52 60 52 57 52 55 l 52 55 b 53 55 54 55 55 55 b 55 54 55 53 55 52 b 57 52 58 52 59 52 b 59 51 59 49 59 48 b 58 48 57 48 55 48 b 55 49 55 51 55 52 b 54 52 53 52 52 52 l 52 52 b 52 51 52 49 52 48 b 51 48 50 48 49 48 b 49 47 49 45 49 44 b 50 44 50 44 51 44 b 51 43 51 42 51 41 b 54 41 57 41 60 41 b 60 40 60 38 60 37 l 60 37 b 60 37 61 37 63 37 b 63 36 63 35 63 34 b 66 34 68 34 70 34 b 70 35 70 36 70 37 l 70 37 b 69 37 68 37 66 37 b 66 38 66 40 66 41 b 65 41 64 41 63 41 b 63 43 63 46 63 48 b 65 48 68 48 70 48 l 70 48 b 70 49 70 51 70 52 b 72 52 73 52 74 52 b 74 55 74 57 74 59 l 74 59 b 73 59 72 59 70 59 b 70 61 70 64 70 67 b 72 67 73 67 74 67 l 74 67 b 74 69 74 71 74 74 b 72 74 71 74 70 74 b 70 75 70 76 70 77 b 69 77 68 77 66 77 b 66 75 66 72 66 70 b 65 70 64 70 63 70 l 63 70 b 63 68 63 65 62 63 b 64 63 65 63 66 63 b 66 61 66 60 66 59 b 65 59 64 59 63 59 b 63 58 63 57 63 55 b 61 55 61 55 59 55 b 59 57 59 58 59 59 b 61 59 62 59 63 59 b 63 60 63 61 63 63 b 60 63 58 63 55 63 b 55 64 55 65 55 66 b 54 66 53 66 52 66 b 52 67 51 68 51 70 b 53 70 54 70 55 70 b 55 71 55 72 55 74 b 53 74 50 74 48 74 l 48 74 b 48 72 48 71 48 70 b 46 70 45 70 45 70
歡迎加入
小願8壓制組
出品
騙子
Lies!
胡扯
Deceptions!
給我看
Let's see it.
菩提·魯克 貨船飛行員
"Bodhi Rook. Cargo pilot."
- 是本地人 - 嗯
- Local boy, huh? - Uh-huh.
這是他被抓時在他鞋子裏找到的.
我聽見了
Okay. I can hear you.
不是他抓住的 是我自願來的 我叛逃了
He didn't capture me. I came here myself. I defected.
叛逃了
I defected.
每天都在撒謊
Every day, more lies.
撒謊 我冒生命危險就是為了撒謊嗎
Lies? Would I risk everything for a lie?
不 我們沒時間了
No, we don't have time for this.
我必須立刻見到索·格瑞拉 否則就晚了
I have to speak to Saw Gerrera before it's too late.
好
Okay.
你 就是
Sorry, you're...
呃
Um...
這是給你的
That's for you.
是我主動交給他們的
And I gave it to them.
不是他們搜的
They did not find it!
給你的
I gave it to them.
蓋倫·厄索
Uh, Galen Erso.
他派我來找你的
He told me to find you.
博·加裏特
Bor Gullet.
Uh, Bor Gullet?
等等 不
What? Wait!
蓋倫·厄索派我來的
Galen Erso sent me!
是他讓我來找你的
He told me to find you.
很不幸
Most unfortunate about
傑達發生了洩密事件 科倫尼克總監
the security breach on Jedha, Director Krennic.
工程屢屢延誤 保密工作又出漏洞
After so many setbacks and delays, and now this.
聽說此事已經傳得滿城風雨了
We've heard word of rumors circulating through the city.
你那個逃跑的貨船飛行員
Apparently, you've lost
還真是口無遮攔
a rather talkative cargo pilot.
如果參議院得知這個項目
If the Senate gets wind of our project,
無數星系都會倒向叛軍
countless systems will flock to the Rebellion.
等這個戰鬥太空站一竣工 塔金總督
When the battle station is finished, Governor Tarkin...
就不用擔心參議院了
the Senate will be of little concern.
不能等了 科倫尼克總監
When has become now, Director Krennic.
皇帝無法再容忍任何延誤
The Emperor will tolerate no further delay.
現在的形勢對叛軍越來越有利了
You have made time an ally of the Rebellion.
我建議一舉解決兩個問題
I suggest we solve both problems simultaneously...
我們現在馬上進行武器的測試
with an immediate test of the weapon.
如果測試失敗的話
Failure will find you explaining why
你要去向陛下親自謝罪
to a far less patient audience.
我不會失敗的
I will not fail.
怎麼了 琴 不要害怕
What's the matter, Jyn? You look frightened.
我會永遠保護你
I'll always protect you.
星辰
Stardust.
勿忘初心
Don't ever change.
相信
Trust.
蓋倫
Galen.
正在進入軌道 你來駕駛
We're coming into orbit. You have controls.
這就是傑達
That's Jedha.
現在的模樣
Or what's left of it.
找到索 就能找到你父親
We find Saw, we find your father.
為什麼有殲星艦
What's with the Destroyer?
因為你的老朋友 索·格瑞拉
It's because of your old friend, Saw Gerrera.
他襲擊了那些貨船隊
He's been attacking the cargo shipments.
他們在運什麼
What are they bringing in?
他們是在掠奪礦石
It's what are they taking out.
凱伯水晶 有多少搶多少
Kyber crystal. All they can get.
原本不明白他們為什麼要掠奪聖殿
We wondered why they were stripping the temple.
現在知道了
Now we know.
那是武器的能量來源
It's the fuel for the weapon.
你父親正在建造的武器
The weapon your father's building.
也許我們應該把那個活靶子留下
Maybe we should leave target practice behind.
你是在指我嗎
Are you talking about me?
她說得對 我們得掩人耳目
She's right. We need to blend in.
你留在船上
Stay with the ship.
我可以掩人耳目 我是帝國機器人
I can blend in. I'm an Imperial droid.
是帝國佔領這座城市
The city is under Imperial occupation.
這裏有一半人想給你重新編程
Half the people here wanna reprogram you.
另一半想在你頭上開個洞
The other half wanna put a hole in your head.
我說你這麼關心我 有什麼企圖嗎
I'm surprised you're so concerned with my safety.
我不關心
I'm not.
只是擔心 他們要是沒瞄準 打中了我
I'm just worried they might miss you and hit me.
聽起來倒不是件壞事
Doesn't sound so bad to me.
博·加裏特
Bor Gullet
可以感知
can feel
你的想法
your thoughts.
不說謊 你就沒事
No lie is safe.
你的真實意圖是什麼 貨船飛行員
What have you really brought me, cargo pilot?
博·加裏特會發現真相
Bor Gullet will know the truth.
可惜有個副作用 測試的對象
The unfortunate side effect is that one tends...
常常會發瘋的
to lose one's mind.
不
No!
嗨
Hey.
你給我小心一點兒
You just watch yourself.
等等 別 別
Wait. No, no.
抱歉 抱歉
Sorry, sir.
我們不是故意的 抱歉
We don't want any trouble. Sorry.
快走 快走
Come on. Come on.
傑達的市民們
Citizens of Jedha.
如果有發現失蹤飛行員的線索
You must come forward with information
請務必報告我們
of the location of this missing cargo pilot.
舉報者將會獲得六百信用幣的獎勵
A reward of 600 credits for the information shall be awarded.
我有個線人
I had a contact.
是索的手下
One of Saw's Rebels.
他最近失蹤了
But he's just gone missing.
他的姐姐一直在找他
His sister will be looking for him.
他姐姐會在被毀的聖殿裏等他
The temple's been destroyed, but she'll be there waiting.
我們會告訴她你的名字
We'll give her your name
希望他能帶我們見到索
and hope that gets us a meeting with Saw.
希望
Hope?
對 起義都建立在希望之上
Yeah. Rebellions are built on hope.
把手放在頭上
Hands where I can see them.
到那邊去
Get over there.
給我看看身份證 進去搜
Show me some identification. Check inside.
都是你的飛行員惹的事
Is this all because of your pilot?
願他人的原力與你同在
May the Force of others be with you.
等我一下
Wait for me.
願他人的原力與你同在
May the Force of others be with you.
你願意用那條項鏈換一個預知命運的機會嗎
Would you trade that necklace for a glimpse into your future?
對
Yes.
我在和你說話
I'm speaking to you.
我是奇魯·英威
I'm Chirrut Imwe.
你怎麼知道我戴著項鏈
How did you know I was wearing a necklace?
想知道你得花錢
For that answer, you must pay.
你瞭解凱伯水晶嗎
What do you know about kyber crystals?
我父親說
My father, he...
它為絕地武士的光劍提供能量
He said they powered the Jedi's lightsabers.
琴
Jyn.
快點兒 該走了
Come on. Let's go.
最強的星星有凱伯水晶之心
The strongest stars have hearts of kyber.
快走
Let's go.
我們不是來這兒交朋友的
We're not here to make friends.
他們是誰
Who are they?
他們是這裏的守衛
The Guardians of the Whills.
凱伯聖殿的保護者
Protectors of the Kyber Temple.
可這裏已經沒有什麼值得保護了
But there's nothing left to protect.
他們現在也只會惹事生非
So now they're just causing trouble for everybody.
你怎麼突然緊張起來了
You seem awfully tense all of a sudden.
我們得快走 這個地方 就要炸翻天了
We have to hurry. This town is ready to blow.
帝國的公民們
Citizens of the Empire...
帝國軍隊堅持不懈地打擊
Imperial forces tirelessly fight
索·格瑞拉的恐怖活動
Saw Gerrera's reign of terror...
正是由於帝國軍隊的努力
over the people of this beloved city.
才得以保衛這座重要的城鎮
Truth and justice are the tools of the Empire.
你應該有備用計劃吧
Tell me you have a backup plan.
偷襲
Incoming!
看來找到索的起義軍了
Looks like we found Saw's rebels.
在上面
Up there!
別去
Jyn, no!
瞄準他們
Hit the terrorist.
快點回來
Get out of there!
凱伯水晶
Kyber...
快來
Come on!
走這邊
This way!
卡西亞
Cassian!
你知道那不是我嗎
Did you know that wasn't me?
噢 當然
Yeah. Of course.
我記得我讓你待在船上的
I thought I told you to stay on the ship.
沒錯 但我覺得很無聊
You did. But I thought it was boring,
而且你們有麻煩了
and you were in trouble.
對於兩個要掩人耳目的人來說
There were a lot of explosions...
- 這動靜也太大了 - 嗨 站住
- for two people blending in. - Freeze!
你說得對
You're right.
我是應該待在船上
I should just wait on the ship.
站住 站那兒別動
Halt. Stop right there.
你帶這些囚犯去哪兒
Where are you taking these prisoners?
這些是囚犯
These are prisoners.
對 你帶他們去哪兒
Yes. Where are you taking them?
我要帶他們去 關押他們的監獄
I am taking them to imprison them in prison.
- 他要帶我們去 - 閉嘴
- He's taking us to... - Quiet!
你要再囉嗦 我就好好收拾你
And there's a fresh one if you mouth off again.
- 囚犯由我們接管 - 不用了
- We'll take them from here. - That's okay.
指給我正確的方向就行
If you could just point me in the right direction,
我能押送他們
I can take them, I'm sure.
- 我已經押著他們走了 - 嗨 等一下
- I've taken them this far. - Hey, wait a second.
- 把他們帶走 - 等等
- Take them away. - Wait.
你不能帶走他們
You can't take them away.
你 待著別動
You. Stay here.
我們要檢查你的系統
We need to check your diagnostics.
檢查我的系統
Diagnostics?
我完全可以自己檢查自己
I'm capable of running my own diagnostics,
謝謝你的好意了
thank you very much.
讓他們走吧
Let them pass in peace.
我說讓他們走
原力與我同在
The Force is with me.
我與原力同在
And I am with the Force.
我無所畏懼
And I fear nothing.
一切都是原力的意願
For all is as the Force wills it.
你 站住別動
Hey, stop right there.
他看不見
He's blind.
他聾了嗎
Is he deaf?
我說了 你不許動
I said stop right there!
你的腳沒事吧
Is your foot all right?
你差點打中我
You almost shot me.
不用客氣
You're welcome.
全部消滅
Clear of hostiles.
- 還差一個 - 他是我們的人
- One hostile. - He's with us.
是自己人
They're all right.
謝謝
Thanks.
卡西亞 抱歉我打了你
Cassian, I'm sorry about the slap.
回船上去 等候我的命令
Go back to the ship. Wait for my call.
他是絕地
Is he a Jedi?
這裏沒有絕地了
There are no Jedi here anymore.
只剩下幾個傻瓜 就像他
Only dreamers like this fool.
原力保佑了我
The Force did protect me.
是我保佑了你
I protected you.
能帶我們見索·格瑞拉嗎
Can you get us to Saw Gerrera?
看清楚了 我們可不是帝國的朋友
Can't you see? We are no friends of the Empire.
你跟那個殺了我們的人的傢伙說吧.
如果你們殺了我和我的朋友
Anyone who kills me or my friends
會被索·格瑞拉問罪的
will answer to Saw Gerrera.
你何出此言？
因為我是蓋倫·厄索的女兒
Because I'm the daughter of Galen Erso.
帶他們走
開玩笑嗎 我是個盲人
Are you kidding me? I'm blind.
原力與我同在 我與原力同在
I'm one with the Force, the Force is with me.
唸咒
You pray?
原力與我同在 我與原力同在
I'm one with the Force, the Force is with me.
真的假的
Really?
原力與我同在 我與原力同在
I'm one with the Force, the Force is with me.
唸咒能把門念開
He's praying for the door to open.
有人煩 是因為他怕我成功
It bothers him because he knows it's possible.
貝茲·瑪彪斯曾經比我們所有的人都虔誠得多
Baze Malbus was once the most devoted Guardian of us all.
我覺得原力和我的意志根本不相吻合
I'm beginning to think the Force and I have different priorities.
放鬆點兒 上尉
Relax, Captain.
我們進過更糟糕的監獄
We've been in worse cages than this one.
我可是第一次
This is the first for me.
監獄有很多種形式 上尉
There is more than one sort of prison, Captain.
我覺得你心裏就有一座
I sense that you carry yours wherever you go.
琴
Jyn.
真的是你
Is it really you?
簡直難以置信
I can't believe it!
是不是大吃一驚
Must be quite a surprise.
我們還是朋友
Are we not still friends?
上次見面
The last time I saw you,
你給了我一把刀一把槍
you gave me a knife and loaded blaster...
讓我在地堡裏等到天亮
and told me to wait in a bunker till daylight.
我知道你不會有事
I knew you were safe.
你丟下我跑了
You left me behind.
你那時已經是我最出色的部下
You were already the best soldier in my cadre.
- 我才16歲 - 我是在保護你
- I was 16! - I was protecting you!
你拋棄了我
You dumped me!
你不知道 你父親是帝國的科學家
You were the daughter of an Imperial science officer.
有人猜出了你的身世
People were starting to figure that out.
他們會把你當做 當做人質的
People who wanted to use you as a hostage.
每天我都在
Not a day goes by...
牽掛著你
that I don't think of you.
但是沒想到
But today...
會是今天
of all days...
只是個圈套
It's a trap.
對吧
Isn't it?
什麼
What?
那個飛行員
The pilot.
那條信息
The message.
這一切
All of it.
難道 你是
Did they send you?
是他們派來
Did you come here...
殺我的
to kill me?
我已經是半死的人
There's not much of me left.
同盟想找我父親
The Alliance wants my father.
據說他給你發了一份武器情報
They think he sent you a message about a weapon.
我想他們派我來
I guess they think by sending me,
是希望你能幫助他們
you might actually help them out.
那你想得到什麼 琴
So what is it that you want, Jyn?
他們讓我做的事 我做了
They wanted an introduction, they've got it.
我要走了
I'm out now.
剩下的事你們自己商量
Rest of you can do what you want.
你放棄了我們的事業
You care not about the cause?
我們的事業
The cause?
你別傻了
Seriously?
同盟
The Alliance...
起義軍 不管是
the rebels, whatever it is
加上什麼冠冕堂皇的名詞
you're calling yourself these days...
只能帶給我痛苦
all it's ever brought me is pain.
你馬上就能看到帝國旗幟
You can stand to see the Imperial flag
插遍整個銀河系
reign across the galaxy?
不抬頭看不就行了
It's not a problem if you don't look up.
給你看樣東西
I have something to show you.
來
Come.
皇帝一直在等我的報告
The Emperor is awaiting my report.
我還以為陛下會和維德大人
One would hope that he and Lord Vader
親臨現場
might've been here for such an occasion.
經過慎重考慮
And I thought it prudent to save you
我不想讓你當眾出醜
from any potential embarrassment.
你的擔心幾乎沒有必要
Your concern's hardly warranted.
那只是你一個人的看法
If saying it would only make it so.
所有的帝國部隊都已經撤離了
All Imperial forces have been evacuated...
我隨時可以摧毀整顆衛星
and I stand ready to destroy the entire moon.
沒必要
That won't be necessary.
我要的是火力演示 不是全國通告
We need a statement, not a manifesto.
僅摧毀聖城就足夠了
The Holy City will be enough for today.
瞄準傑達城
Target Jedha City.
準備單反應堆點火
Prepare single reactor ignition.
長官 已經就位 我們
Sir, we're in position...
開火
Fire!
啟動主點火程序
Commence primary ignition.
隔壁牢房是誰
Who's the one in the next cell?
什麼
What?
哪兒
Where?
一個帝國的飛行員
An Imperial pilot.
- 飛行員 - 我要宰了他
- Pilot? - I'm gonna kill him!
- 等等 等等 - 過來
- No, no. No, wait! - Come here!
不
No!
退後 退後
Back off! Back off!
好了 沒事了
Okay, okay.
你是飛行員
Are you the pilot?
嗨 嗨
Hey. Hey.
你是那個貨船飛行員嗎
Are you the pilot? The shuttle pilot?
飛行員
Pilot?
他怎麼了
What's wrong with him?
蓋倫·厄索
Galen Erso.
你認識他嗎
You know that name?
我帶來了信息 我是飛行員
I brought the message. I'm the pilot.
我是飛行員
I'm the pilot.
是嗎 太好了
Okay. Good.
那麼蓋倫·厄索在哪兒
Now where is Galen Erso?
準備就緒
Stand by.
這就是我收到的信息
This is the message I was sent.
索 如果你看到這條信息
Saw, if you are watching this...
可能還有機會去挽救同盟
then perhaps there's a chance to save the Alliance.
還有機會讓我進行自我辯解
Perhaps there's a chance to explain myself...
雖然我不敢抱太大的希望
and, though I don't dare hope for too much...
可能有機會救琴 如果她還活著
a chance for Jyn, if she's alive...
如果你能找到她的話
if you can possibly find her...
請你告訴她 我對她的愛從來沒有改變過
to let her know that my love for her has never faded...
我始終在思念著她
and how desperately I've missed her.
琴 我的星塵
Jyn, my Stardust...
我不敢想像你會怎麼看我
I can't imagine what you think of me.
我被帶走的時候 承受著痛苦的事實
When I was taken, I faced some bitter truths.
他們對我說
I was told that soon enough
科倫尼克很快會抓住你
Krennic would have you as well.
後來我不斷地想
As time went by...
你也許死了
I knew that you were either dead...
也許躲過了他們的搜捕
or so well hidden that he would never find you.
我知道如果我拒絕合作 如果我自殺
I knew if I had refused to work, if I took my own life...
那麼用不了多久 科倫尼克就會發現
it would only be a matter of time before Krennic realized...
沒有我 他也能完成項目
he no longer needed me to complete the project.
但是有件事他沒有想到
So I did the one thing nobody expected.
我騙了他
I lied.
我學會了欺騙
I learned to lie.
我扮演著絕望潦倒的角色
I played the part of a beaten man
靠工作來麻醉自己
resigned to the sanctuary of his work.
我讓自己變得不可或缺
I made myself indispensable...
同時 還埋下了復仇的種子
and all the while, I laid the groundwork of my revenge.
我們叫它 死星
We call it the Death Star.
這座名副其實的死亡行星
There is no better name...
很快就會正式竣工
and the day is coming soon when it will be unleashed.
我在系統深處設計了一個漏洞
I've placed a weakness deep within the system...
一個小到他們無法找到的致命缺陷
a flaw so small and powerful, they will never find it.
但是 琴
But, Jyn...
如果你能聽到 我的愛女
Jyn, if you're listening, my beloved...
我的一生已經白白耗盡了
so much of my life has been wasted.
我只有 在最堅強的時候
I try to think of you only in the moments when I'm strong...
才敢想起你 一想到失去你
because the pain of not having you with me...
和你母親 我們的家庭
your mother, our family.
那種痛苦刻骨銘心
The pain of that loss is so overwhelming...
我現在仍然難以承受
I risk failing even now.
我又怎麼能不想你呢
It's just so hard not to think of you.
你到底在什麼地方
Think of where you are...
我的星塵
my Stardust.
索
Saw...
反應堆模塊是關鍵部位
the reactor module, that's the key.
我在那裏設計了陷阱
That's the place I've laid my trap.
它很隱蔽 但很不穩定
It's well hidden and unstable.
只要局部發生爆炸 就會摧毀整座太空站
One blast to any part of it will destroy the entire station.
你需要設計圖
You'll need the plans...
有了死星結構設計圖 才能找到反應堆
the structural plans for the Death Star, to find the reactor.
我知道斯卡裏夫的塔堡數據庫裏
I know there's a complete engineering archive...
存有一套完整的工程檔案
in the data vault at the Citadel Tower on Scarif.
反應堆模塊的高壓一旦爆炸
Any pressurized explosion to the reactor module...
就會觸發連鎖反應 摧毀整座太空站
will set off a chain reaction that will destroy the entire station.
走 走
Go, go!
K-2 K-2 你在哪兒
K-2, K-2! Where are you?
終於說話了
There you are.
我一直在等待你的命令
I'm standing by as you requested...
你猜我看到了什麼 卡西亞
although there's a problem on the horizon.
消失的地平線
There's no horizon.
標記我們的方位 把船開過來 快
Locate our position. Bring that ship in here, now!
你要去哪兒
Where are you going?
我去找琴
I gotta find Jyn.
帶上飛行員 我們需要他
Get the pilot, we need him!
好吧
All right.
飛行員交給我了
I'll get the pilot.
飛行員
Pilot.
別 別 別
No, no, no!
跟我走
Let's go.
琴
Jyn!
嗨
Hey.
我們得走了
We gotta go.
我知道你父親在哪兒了
I know where your father is.
跟他走 琴
Go with him, Jyn.
快點走
You must go!
跟我們走吧
Come with us.
我不會再逃跑了
I will run no longer.
- 快走 - 但你必須活下去
- Come on. - But you must save yourself.
- 快走 - 走
- Come on. - Go!
沒時間了
There's no time!
拯救義軍
Save the Rebellion!
拯救夢想
Save the dream.
噢 太美了
Oh, it's beautiful.
奇魯 快走
Chirrut, let's go!
快走
Come on!
快離開這兒
Let's get out of here!
Get us out of here!
快走
Punch it!
我們的存活機率不太樂觀
I'm not very optimistic about our odds.
閉嘴 K
Not now, K.
快點兒
Come on!
加速
Punch it.
抱歉 我還沒有完成運算
I haven't completed my calculations.
我來幫你算
I'll make them for you.
我應該向你道歉 科倫尼克總監
I believe I owe you an apology, Director Krennic.
你的成果完全超出了預期
Your work exceeds all expectations.
你會如實稟報皇帝嗎
And you'll tell the Emperor as much?
我會告訴他 對你頻頻失誤的耐心
I will tell him that his patience with your misadventures...
終於換回了
has been rewarded with a weapon
一種可以迅速終止叛亂的武器
that will bring a swift end to the Rebellion.
但是這還只是它全部實力的
And that that was only an inkling
一點鋒芒而已
of its destructive potential.
我還將告訴他 我會立即接管
I will tell him that I will be taking control over the weapon...
這個多年以前 我最先提議建造的武器
I first spoke of years ago effective immediately.
這一切 根本就是我的成就
We stand here amidst my achievement.
不是你的
Not yours!
我想最近的安全漏洞已經暴露了
I'm afraid the recent security breaches...
你所欠缺的軍事領導力
have laid bare your inadequacies as a military director.
漏洞我已經補上了
The breaches have been filled.
傑達也已經被消滅了
Jedha has been silenced.
那個飛行員並非擅自行動
You think this pilot acted alone?
已經查清楚了 他來自伊杜基地
He was dispatched from the installation on Eadu...
蓋倫·厄索的研究中心
Galen Erso's facility.
我們會搞清的
Oh, we'll see about this.
安多上尉的加密信息 長官
A coded message from Captain Andor, sir.
武器情報屬實
"Weapon confirmed."
傑達已經被摧毀
"Jedha destroyed."
任務目標位於伊杜 請指示
"Mission target located on Eadu, please advise."
被摧毀
Destroyed?
回電
Proceed.
告訴他原來的命令維持不變
Tell him my orders still stand.
必須讓他加快速度
Tell him to proceed with haste...
嚴格執行計劃
and keep to the plan.
我們不知道他還在為帝國建造什麼
We have no idea what he's building for the Empire.
必須抓住機會 除掉蓋倫·厄索
We have to kill Galen Erso while we have the chance.
貝茲 告訴我
Baze, tell me.
全沒了嗎
All of it?
整座城市
The whole city?
告訴我
Tell me.
全沒了
All of it.
我明白了
Understood.
我們現在前往伊杜
Set course for Eadu.
正在設定航線
Setting course for Eadu.
我父親在那兒嗎
Is that where my father is?
我相信是
I think so.
你是蓋倫的女兒
So you're Galen's daughter?
你認識他
You know him?
我是菩提 那個飛行員
I am Bodhi, the pilot.
信息是你帶來的
You brought the message.
是的
Yes.
你父親
Your father...
他跟我說可以將功補過
he said I could get right by myself.
他說我可以糾正錯誤
He said I could make it right...
只要我聽從自己
if I was brave enough...
敢於挺身而出
to listen to what was in my heart.
可惜現在
Do something about it.
現在已經晚了
Guess it was too late.
現在還不晚
It wasn't too late.
對我來說 的確是太晚了
Seems pretty late to me.
不
No.
我們可以打敗那些兇手
We can beat the people who did this.
我父親的信息 我看到了
My father's message, I've seen it.
他們叫它死星
They call it the Death Star.
但是他們不知道
But they have no idea...
死星有個弱點
there's a way to defeat it.
你冤枉了我父親
You're wrong about my father.
反正是他造的
He did build it.
因為他知道有沒有他都一樣
Because he knew they'd do it without him.
我父親做了決定
My father made a choice.
為起義軍他不惜犧牲自己
He sacrificed himself for the Rebellion.
他在武器上設計了陷阱
He's rigged a trap inside it.
所以他派你來傳遞信息
That's why he sent you, to bring that message.
在哪兒
Where is it?
信息在哪兒
Where's the message?
是一段全息錄像
It was a hologram.
你拿到信息了 對嗎
You have that message, right?
當時情況緊急
Everything happened so fast.
你看過嗎
Did you see it?
你不相信我
You don't believe me?
你要說服的人不是我
I'm not the one you've got to convince.
我相信她
I believe her.
那她得謝謝你
That's good to know.
是什麼樣的陷阱
What kind of trap?
你說你爸爸設了個陷阱
You said your father made a trap.
反應堆 他設計了一個結構缺陷
The reactor. He's placed a weakness there.
他隱瞞了多年
He's been hiding it for years.
如果你炸掉反應堆模塊
He said if you can blow the reactor,
整個系統就會崩潰
the module, the whole system goes down.
你必須報告同盟
You need to send word to the Alliance.
我剛報告過
I've done that.
他們必須知道有辦法摧毀武器
They have to know there's a way to destroy this thing.
必須去斯卡裏夫竊取設計圖
They have to go to Scarif to get the plans.
我不能冒險發送信息
I can't risk sending that.
我們已經深入帝國境內了
We're in the heart of Imperial territory.
那我們應該去救他回來
Then we'll find him and bring him back.
他可以親自告訴他們
And he can tell them himself.
伊杜航線設定完畢 長官
Course set for Eadu, sir.
帝國凱伯水晶精煉廠
伊杜
我與原力同在 原力與我同在
I'm one with the Force, the Force is with me.
右轉20度
20 degrees to the right.
仰角10度
10 degrees up.
再低一點兒 低一點兒
Lower, lower, lower. Lower!
你確定是這個方向嗎
Are you sure this is the way?
他們有追蹤器
They have landing trackers here.
還有戰鬥機巡邏
They have patrol squadrons.
我們必須在低空飛行
You've got to stay in the canyon. Keep it low.
小心右邊
Watch your right!
失敗概率26%
There's a 26% chance of failure.
我們還有多遠
How much farther?
我不知道 不確定 我沒去過那條路線
I don't know, I'm not sure. I never really come this way.
很近了 我知道很近了
But we're close, we're close. I know that.
失敗概率35%
Now, there's a 35% chance of failure.
我不想知道 謝謝
I don't wanna know. Thank you!
我懂你
I understand.
降落 趕快降落
Now! Put it down, now!
風太大
The wind.
再往前  我們就飛過穿梭機站了
If you keep going, you'll be right over the shuttle depot.
- 小心 - K
- Watch out! - K!
大家抓緊
Hold on tight!
我們要迫降了
We're coming down hard!
繼續呼叫
Try them again.
遵命 長官 可是
I am, sir. We...
我們信號消失了
The signal's gone dead.
戰鬥機起飛
Squadron up.
目標 伊杜
Target Eadu.
怎麼樣 檢查了穩定器
How about now? Check stabilizers.
菩提 實驗室在哪兒
Bodhi, where's the lab?
你問研究中心嗎
The research facility?
對 在哪兒
Yeah. Where is it?
翻過那座山就是
It's just over that ridge.
我們正前方應該是一個穿梭機站
That's a shuttle depot straight ahead of us.
- 你確定嗎 - 確定
- You are sure of that? - Yes.
但願我們能
We'll have to hope
從那裏偷出一艘帝國飛船
there's still an Imperial ship left to steal.
我的計劃是這樣的
Here's what we're doing.
風暴暫時還不會停 正好可以掩護我們
Hopefully the storm keeps up and keeps us hidden down here.
菩提 你跟我一起走
Bodhi, you're coming with me.
我們去山脊上查看情況
We'll go up the ridge and check it out.
我們跟你們一起去
I'm coming with you.
不 你父親的信息
No, your father's message.
你是送信人 你不能冒險
We can't risk it. You're the messenger.
這算什麼邏輯 我們大家都知道
That's ridiculous, we all got the message.
信息內容
Everyone here knows it.
只要我們炸掉反應堆模塊
"One blast to the reactor module
整個系統就會崩潰
"and the whole system goes down."
這是你說的 整個系統就會崩潰
That's how you said it, "The whole system goes down."
快去檢查通訊器
Get to work fixing our comms.
我現在只想知道 我們當前到底是什麼處境
All I want to do right now is get a handle on what we're up against.
所以我們得小心翼翼地爬上山
So we're gonna go very small and very careful up the rise...
去觀察敵情
and see what's what.
我們走
Let's get outta here.
他長得像殺人犯嗎
Does he look like a killer?
不像 我看他沒殺過人
No. He has the face of a friend.
你們在說誰呢
Who are you talking about?
安多上尉
Captain Andor.
什麼意思
Why'd you ask that?
你為什麼問他 像不像殺人犯
What do you mean, "Does he look like a killer?"
想要行兇的人
The Force moves darkly
周圍的原力會變得陰暗
near a creature that's about to kill.
他的武器現在處於狙擊模式
His weapon was in the sniper configuration.
這兒不行 我們要繼續往上
No, no, no. We've got to go up.
這裏根本看不清楚
You can't see much from down there.
走這邊
This way.
我在你後面
I'll be right behind you.
快走
Come on.
你上哪兒去
Where are you going?
我去跟著琴
I'm gonna follow Jyn.
她的蹤跡很清晰
Her path is clear.
你自己
Alone?
祝你好運
Good luck!
我不需要好運 有你呢
I don't need luck. I have you!
他們在幹嘛
What are they doing?
如果卡西亞回來 可不會等他們的
If Cassian comes back, we're leaving without them.
能看見厄索嗎
You see Erso out there?
我們走得太遠了
We've come too far.
耐心點兒 朋友
Patience, my friend.
是他
That's him.
蓋倫·厄索 深色衣服
That's him. Galen, in the dark suit.
你下山去 趕快找一艘飛船
Get back down there and find us a ride outta here.
你要幹什麼
Well, what are you doing?
別管我
You heard me.
你說我們只是來看一眼的
You said we came up here just to have a look.
我來了 我在看 快去
I'm here, I'm looking. Go.
快去
Hurry!
我有好消息 蓋倫
Excellent news, Galen.
戰鬥太空站已經竣工了
The battle station is complete.
你一定非常自豪
You must be very proud.
那是應該的 科倫尼克
Proud as I can be, Krennic.
召集工程師 我有事宣佈
Gather your engineers. I have an announcement.
到齊了嗎
Is that all of them?
齊了
Yes.
先生們 你們中間
Gentlemen, one of you...
有人背叛了帝國
betrayed the Empire.
有人居然串通了一名飛行員
One of you has conspired with a pilot...
向叛軍洩露情報
to send messages to the Rebellion.
我奉勸這個叛徒
And I urge that traitor...
立刻自首
step forward.
看來
Very well...
你們是集體叛國了
I'll consider it a group effort then.
預備
Ready!
- 不 不 - 瞄準
- No! No! - Aim!
開火
And fire!
不 不 不
Stop! Stop! Stop!
科倫尼克 住手
Krennic, stop!
是我幹的
It was me!
跟他們沒有關係
They have nothing to do with it.
放了他們
Spare them.
開火
Fire!
我是怎麼知道武器完工的
How do I know the weapon is complete?
你想讓我來跟你分享一些細節嗎
Let me share with you some details.
卡西安
Cassian.
卡西安 你能聽到嗎
Cassian, can you hear me?
我在 看來你修好了
I'm here. You've got it working?
修是修好了 但我們有麻煩了
Affirmative, yes. Although we have a problem.
同盟戰鬥機中隊正在逼近 趕快撤離
There's an Alliance squadron approaching. Clear the area.
不 不 不 不 讓他們停止攻擊
No, no, no, no! Tell them to hold off!
琴在那個平台上呢
Jyn's on that platform.
傑達
Jedha...
索·格瑞拉 和他的極端組織
Saw Gerrera. His band of fanatics...
他們的聖城
their Holy City...
那些絕地最後的遺跡 都沒了
the last reminder of the Jedi, gone.
你不會得逞的
You'll never win.
這話我聽著很耳熟
Now where have I heard that before?
我代安多上尉轉達
Relay from Captain Andor.
將軍
General.
安多上尉要求 暫緩戰鬥機支援
Captain Andor requesting a delay on squadron support.
現場有同盟軍成員 請回復
Alliance forces on site. Please confirm.
呼叫中隊長 停止攻擊
Get the squadron leader on. Get him on now!
已經開始了 長官
They're already engaged, sir.
琴 不
Jyn. No.
開火還擊 進入戰鬥位置
Return fire! To your stations!
讓戰機立即起飛
Get our fighters in the air now!
爸爸
Father!
收到 從3區飛往7區
Roger that. 3 through 7.
撤退 撤退
Fall back! Fall back!
總監 我們必須撤離
Director, we need to evacuate.
爸爸 我是琴
Papa. Papa, it's me.
是我
It's Jyn.
琴
Jyn?
我的星塵
Stardust.
爸爸
Papa.
我看到了你的信息
I've seen your message.
我看到了全息錄像
The hologram, I've seen it.
你必須摧毀它
It must be destroyed.
我知道 我會的
I know. I know.
我們會的
We will.
琴
Jyn.
看看你
Look at you.
我有好多話要對你說
I have so much to tell you.
爸爸
Papa.
不
No.
不 爸爸
No! Papa.
爸爸 你醒醒
Papa, come on!
在那兒 幹掉他們
Over there! Take 'em down.
醒醒 爸爸 醒醒
Come on. Papa. Come on.
琴 我們得走了 快來
Jyn, we gotta go. Come on.
不行
I can't leave him.
聽我說 他死了
Listen to me, he's gone.
你什麼也做不了 快來
Nothing you can do. Come on.
- 我不能離開他 - 快來
- I can't leave him. - Come on!
我不走
I can't.
走
Move!
- 這邊 這邊 - 趴下
- This way, this way! - Down!
快走 快走
Come on! Come on!
幹得漂亮
Well done.
你也成起義軍了
You're a rebel now.
好了 快點兒
Let's go! Let's go!
快點走
Come on, let's move!
快點兒 撤離基地
Come on, let's get out of here!
快 快 快
Move, move, move!
好了 K-2 趕快起飛
Okay, K-2. Let's go!
收到了
Copy that.
收住離子推進器 先飛出風暴區
Ion thrusters low until we've cleared the storm.
明白
Understood.
你騙了我
You lied to me.
你別激動
You're in shock.
你是去殺我父親
You went up there to kill my father.
你知道你自己在說什麼嗎
You don't know what you're talking about.
敢否認嗎
Deny it.
你現在有點情緒激動 想發洩
You're in shock and looking for some place to put it.
這種反應很正常
I've seen it before.
你不敢否認
I bet you have.
對嗎
They know.
你騙了我們 你為什麼來這兒 你為什麼一個人上山
You lied about why we came here and you lied about why you went up alone.
老實說 我完全有機會扣下扳機
I had every chance to pull the trigger...
我開槍了嗎
but did I?
開了嗎
Did I?
還不如開槍
You might as well have.
我父親掌握著重要情報
My father was living proof...
可你害了他
and you put him at risk.
是同盟的炸彈炸死了他
Those were Alliance bombs that killed him.
我有軍令在身
I had orders...
可是我卻違抗了命令
orders that I disobeyed.
你是不會明白這些的
But you wouldn't understand that.
你知道
Orders?
那是錯誤的命令
When you know they're wrong?
你跟衝鋒隊有什麼區別
You might as well be a Stormtrooper.
你懂什麼
What do you know?
我們沒權利挑三揀四
We don't all have the luxury of deciding...
選擇在乎什麼 不在乎什麼
when and where we want to care about something.
你才剛剛知道起義軍的真面目
Suddenly the Rebellion is real for you.
我是親身經歷過
Some of us live it.
告訴你我參加戰鬥的時候我才六歲
I've been in this fight since I was 6 years old.
這世上不是只有你失去了一切
You're not the only one who lost everything.
我們決定了 一定要改變這個世界
Some of us just decided to do something about it.
這根本不是什麼理由
You can't talk your way around this.
我需要理由
I don't have to.
回雅文四號
Yavin 4.
確認他們知道我們開著偷來的船
Make sure they know we're coming in with a stolen ship.
誰還有問題
Anybody else?
穆斯塔法
大人 科倫尼克總監
My lord, Director Krennic...
已經到了
has arrived.
科倫尼克總監
Director Krennic.
維德大人
Lord Vader.
你似乎有點緊張
You seem unsettled.
不
No...
只是 日程緊張
just pressed for time.
公務有些繁忙
There's a great many things to attend to.
抱歉打斷你
My apologies.
你的確有很多問題需要解釋
You do have a great many things to explain.
我按照皇帝的要求交付了武器
I delivered the weapon the Emperor requested.
應該 應該給我一個機會
I deserve an audience...
確保皇帝陛下清楚地瞭解其全部的
to make certain that he understands its remarkable...
威力
potential.
難道這武器製造麻煩的威力還不夠大嗎
Its power to create problems has certainly been confirmed.
一座城市被毀
A city destroyed...
一座帝國基地遭到襲擊
an Imperial facility openly attacked.
這些都是塔金總督建議試驗的
It was Governor Tarkin that suggested the test.
我不想聽你搖尾乞憐 科倫尼克總監
You were not summoned here to grovel, Director Krennic.
可 可是我
No...
根本就沒有什麼死星
There is no Death Star.
我們已經通知參議院
The Senate has been informed...
傑達完全毀於採礦事故
that Jedha was destroyed in a mining disaster.
是的 大人
Yes, my lord.
我希望你恪盡職守 盡快向皇帝證明
I expect you not to rest until you can assure the Emperor...
蓋倫·厄索沒有以任何方式
that Galen Erso has not compromised
暗中破壞這座武器
this weapon in any way.
那我還擁有指揮權嗎
So I'm still in command?
您會向皇帝說明這些嗎
You'll speak to the Emperor about...
記住 不要被野心卡住喉嚨
Be careful  not to choke on your aspirations,
科倫尼克總監
Director.
我們必須解散艦隊
We must scatter the fleet.
投降是唯一的出路
We have no recourse but to surrender.
難道我們費盡心血建立的一切
Are we really talking about disbanding something...
就這麼付之東流了嗎
that we've worked so hard to create?
我們不能這麼屈服
We can't just give in!
我們加入的是同盟 不是自殺社團
We joined an alliance, not a suicide pact.
我們剛把部隊都集結起來
We've only now managed to gather our forces.
集結部隊
Gather our forces?
但瑞文將軍已經炸翻了一座帝國基地了
General Draven's already blown up an Imperial base.
我必須當機立斷
A decision needed to be made!
如果想發動戰爭
If it's war you want...
你自己去吧
you'll fight alone.
既然如此 又何必建立同盟呢
If that's how it's going, why have an alliance at all?
如果她說的是真的 我們必須立即採取行動
If she's telling the truth, we need to act now!
請保持冷靜
Councilors, please.
很簡單
It is simple.
目前帝國有大規模殺傷性武器
The Empire has the means of mass destruction...
而起義軍沒有
the Rebellion does not.
什麼死星 這不可能
A Death Star. This is nonsense.
我父親有什麼理由說謊
What reason would my father have to lie?
這對他有什麼好處
What benefit would it bring him?
這是想引誘我們進行決戰
To lure our forces into a final battle
然後把我們一舉殲滅
to destroy us once and for all.
如此冒險 根據是什麼
Risk everything? Based on what?
一個罪犯的證詞
The testimony of a criminal?
就憑她的父親 一個帝國科學家的臨終遺言
The dying words of her father, an Imperial scientist?
別忘了還有帝國飛行員
But don't forget the Imperial pilot.
我父親犧牲自己 是好讓我們有機會獲勝
My father gave his life so that we may have a chance to defeat this.
這是你的說法
So you've told us.
如果帝國有強大的武力
If the Empire has this kind of power,
我們還有什麼機會
what chance do we have?
What chance do we have?
應該問 我們還有什麼選擇
The question is "what choice."
逃跑 躲起來
Run, hide...
祈求寬恕 解散軍隊
plead for mercy, scatter your forces.
如果你們屈服於如此邪惡如此強大的敵人
You give way to an enemy this evil with this much power...
銀河系將會陷入永無止境的壓迫
and you condemn the galaxy to an eternity of submission.
- 此時不戰更待何時 - 對
- The time to fight is now! - Yes.
現在每浪費一秒
Every moment you waste
我們都可能成為下一個傑達
is another step closer to the ashes of Jedha.
她到底想說什麼
What is she proposing?
讓她說完
Just let the girl speak.
派精銳部隊去斯卡裏夫
Send your best troops to Scarif.
馬上出動義軍艦隊
Send the rebel fleet if you have to.
你們必須拿到死星計劃圖
You need to capture the Death Star plans
這是摧毀它的唯一希望
if there's any hope of destroying it.
你的意思 難道要我們只靠希望
You're asking us to invade an Imperial installation...
去入侵帝國基地嗎
based on nothing but hope.
起義都建在希望之上
Rebellions are built on hope.
已經沒有希望了
There is no hope.
我們應該戰鬥
I say we fight.
我認為起義軍已經完了
I say the Rebellion is finished!
很抱歉 琴
I'm sorry, Jyn.
如果沒有委員會的一致支持
Without the full support of the Council...
風險太大了
the odds are too great.
辛朵拉將軍
General Syndulla,
請到指令室
please report to the briefing room.
把事談砸了
You don't look happy.
他們都寧願投降
They prefer to surrender.
那你呢
And you?
她是想 跟他們拼了
She wants to fight.
我也想 我們都想
So do I. We all do.
原力是強大的
The Force is strong.
只有我們四個人恐怕還不夠
I'm not sure four of us is quite enough.
我們需要多少人
How many do we need?
你有什麼辦法嗎
What are you talking about?
他們永遠不會相信你的
They were never gonna believe you.
太感謝你的幫助了
I appreciate the support.
我相信
But I do.
我相信你
I believe you.
我們志願參戰
We'd like to volunteer.
他們中
Some of us...
大部分人
Well, most of us...
都為起義軍做過不為人知的事情
we've all done terrible things on behalf of the Rebellion.
間諜
Spies...
搞破壞 暗殺
saboteurs, assassins.
我做的一切 都是為了起義軍
Everything I did, I did for the Rebellion.
當我每次做了那些
And every time I walked away...
我不願記得的事
from something I wanted to forget...
我都告訴自己 那是為了我信仰的事業
I told myself it was for a cause that I believed in.
它值得我這麼做
A cause that was worth it.
否則我會 迷失自己
Without that, we're lost.
我們所做的一切都會毫無意義
Everything we've done would have been for nothing.
如果現在放棄 我無法面對自己
I couldn't face myself if I gave up now.
他們也是
None of us could.
這一路可不太舒服
It won't be comfortable.
有點擠 不過都能塞下
It'd be a bit cramped, but we'd all fit.
可以走嗎
We could go.
好了 出發
Okay. Gear up.
把能帶的東西都帶上
Grab anything that's not nailed down.
走 走 走
Go, go, go!
琴
Jyn.
我會保護你的
I'll be there for you.
卡西安非要我這麼做
Cassian said I had to.
我真的不習慣 讓別人替我去冒險
I'm not used to people sticking around when things go bad.
歡迎回家
Welcome home.
願原力與我們同在
May the Force be with us.
貨運穿梭機請回話
Cargo shuttle, read back please.
到底怎麼回事
What's going on out there?
這艘船已經被禁止起飛了
That ship's off-limits.
任何人不得登船
No one's supposed to be on board until further instructions.
是的 可我們收到了
Yes, yes, we are.
收到命令了
Affirmative.
這是被扣押的帝國飛船
That's an impounded Imperial ship.
你們的呼叫代號是什麼
What's your call sign, pilot?
- 呃 - 我們該走了
- Um... - We have to go.
代號是
It's, um...
隨便說點什麼
Say something.
快點兒
Come on.
俠盜
Rogue.
俠盜一號
Rogue One.
Rogue One?
這裏沒有什麼俠盜一號
There is no Rogue One!
現在有了
Well, there is now.
俠盜一號 準備起飛
Rogue One, pulling away.
準備起飛
Pulling away.
不管其他人怎麼說 戰爭已經無法避免了
Despite what the others say, war is inevitable.
我同意你說的
Yes, I agree.
我必須回奧德朗告訴民眾
I must return to Alderaan to inform my people
和平已經沒有希望了
that there will be no peace.
我們需要團結一切力量
We will need every advantage.
你的朋友
Your friend...
絕地武士
the Jedi.
在克隆人戰爭時期
He served me well during the Clone Wars...
他曾為我效力 躲過了皇帝的大清洗
and has lived in hiding since the Emperor's purge.
我會派人聯絡他
Yes, I will send for him.
一定要派你信任的人
You will need someone you can trust.
他是絕對可靠的人選
I would trust her with my life.
- 安第列斯船長 - 是 先生
- Captain Antilles. - Senator.
交給你個任務
I have a mission for you, sir.
帝國綜合安保中心
斯卡裏夫
好了 我們到了
Okay. We're coming in.
整個行星被護盾包圍
There's a planet-wide defensive shield...
只有一個主閘門
with a single main entry gate.
穿梭機上應該有一個許可代碼
This shuttle should be equipped with
可以讓我們進去
an access code that allows us through.
但前提是帝國還沒有發現它過期
Assuming the Empire hasn't logged it as overdue.
如果發現了呢
And if they have?
閘門會被關閉
Then they shut the gate.
我們哪兒也去不了
And we're all annihilated
都會死在黑暗的太空裏
in the cold, dark vacuum of space.
我死不了
Not me.
我在太空中也能活
I can survive in space.
好了
Okay.
開始吧
Here goes.
貨運穿梭機SW-0608 申請著陸平台
Cargo shuttle SW-0608 requesting a landing pad.
貨運穿梭機SW-0608
Cargo shuttle SW-0608,
你不在抵達日程表上
you're not listed on the arrival schedule.
明白 閘門控制中心
Acknowledged, Gate Control.
我們更改了航程 來自伊杜飛行站
We were rerouted from Eadu flight station.
正在發送許可代碼
Transmitting clearance code now.
正在發送
Transmitting.
貨運穿梭機SW-0608
Cargo shuttle, SW-0608...
- 你被獲准進入 - 太好了
- you are cleared for entry. - Yes!
幹得漂亮
Impressive.
我要去告訴其他人
I'll tell the others.
好極了
Okay.
牽引機測試在2號至8號泊位
Tractor beam test in bays 2 through 8.
SW-0608 獲准9號著陸平台
SW-0608, cleared for Landing Pad 9.
請確認
Acknowledge, please.
SW-0608 正前往9號平台著陸
SW-0608 proceeding to LP 9 as instructed.
下面那座主樓是什麼
Main building down there, what is it?
那就是塔堡
That's the Citadel Tower.
裏面存放著所有帝國的建築檔案
They keep all the Imperial structural archives up there.
設計圖肯定就在那裏
If the plans are anywhere, they'll be there.
塔頂的碟型天線有什麼用途
And the dish at the top, what's it for?
也許發送數據需要很強的信號
I guess it takes a lot of signal to send those data files out.
起落架 已經展開
Landing track, engaged.
起落架鎖定
Landing track locked.
要著陸了
We're landing.
準備出發
We're coming in.
索·格瑞拉說過
Saw Gerrera used to say...
當一個戰士準備豁出性命
one fighter with a sharp stick
那他就能戰勝任何對手
and nothing left to lose can take the day.
他們不知道我們來了
They've no idea we're coming.
我們一定能出奇制勝
They've no reason to expect us.
如果我們成功著陸
If we can make it to the ground,
就抓住了一個機會
we'll take the next chance.
再下一個機會 直到我們贏得勝利
And the next. On and on until we win...
如果運氣好的話
or the chances are spent.
死星設計圖就在下面
The Death Star plans are down there.
卡西亞 K-2 和我會找到設計圖
Cassian, K-2, and I will find them.
沒有什麼能阻止我們
We'll find a way to find them.
梅爾西
Melshi...
帕奧
Pao...
瑪彪斯 英威
Baze, Chirrut...
你們帶領主力
you'll take the main squad.
繞過飛船向東迂迴
Move east and get wide of the ship.
在這裏和塔堡之間設伏
Find a position between here and the tower.
進入最佳攻擊地點
Once you get to the best spot...
把這裏炸翻
light the place up.
動靜搞得越大越好
Make 10 men feel like 100.
把士兵從我們身邊引開
And get those troopers away from us.
我做什麼
What should I do?
保證引擎正常
Keep the engine running.
撤離的時候就指望你了
You're our only way outta here.
貨運穿梭機SW-0608
Cargo shuttle SW-0608...
準備接受檢查 準備接受檢查
be prepared to receive inspection team.
好了嗎
Ready?
你好
Hello.
嗨
Hey.
你們是 是不是要看貨物清單
Oh, you're probably looking for a manifest?
拿給我看看吧
That would be helpful.
就在下面
It's just down here.
科倫尼克總監
Director Krennic,
我們正在通過護盾閘門
we are entering the Scarif shield gate.
並且已經通知了拉姆達將軍
General Ramda has been informed of your arrival.
祝你好運
Good luck...
我的妹子
little sister.
出發 周圍安全了
Go! Go now! You're clear!
好 我們走 快走 快走 快走
All right, let's go! Come on. Move, move, move.
925-H 前往運輸控制中心
925-H to transport control.
我現在有種不祥的
I've got a bad feeling about...
- K - 安靜
- K! - Quiet!
怎麼了
What?
我們需要地圖
We need a map.
我們要不要找個人問問路
Well, I'm sure there's one just lying about.
你知道該怎麼做
You know what you have to do.
每個平台一枚
One per pad.
自行安放 把敵人引出來
Pick your spot. We wanna draw them out.
等我下令引爆 快去
I'll call the timing. Go!
嗨 你聽說了嗎
Hey, did you hear the rumors?
嗯 T-15 被淘汰了
Yeah, the T-15s have been marked obsolete.
是啊 是該被淘汰了
Oh boy, it's about time for that.
嗨
Hey!
怎麼回事
What the...
總監閣下 您怎麼來斯卡裏夫了
Director, what brings you to Scarif?
因為蓋倫·厄索
Galen Erso.
他發出的每一封信息
I want every dispatch,
每一段通訊 你們都給我調出來
every transmission he has ever sent...
仔細地檢查
called up for inspection.
全部嗎
All of them?
對 全部
Yes, all of them.
還不快去
Get started.
K
K.
前往數據庫的最佳路線上
Our optimal route to the data vault
只有89名衝鋒隊隊員
places only 89 Stormtroopers in our path.
而我們只能活著走完全程的33%
We will make it no more than 33% of the way before we are killed.
梅爾西 請回話
Melshi, talk to me.
好了 都好了 請下命令
Ready. Ready. Standing by.
動手吧
Light it up.
加油
Come on.
你們都瞎了嗎
Are we blind?
馬上給我派出駐防軍
Deploy the garrison!
快去
Move!
敵人來了
Troopers!
敵人在左翼
Troopers! Troopers on the left.
進來 進來
Get in! Get in!
長官
Sir, it's Scarif base.
斯卡裏夫基地遭到叛軍襲擊
They're reporting a Rebel incursion.
給我聯絡科倫尼克總監
I want to speak with Director Krennic.
他已經去了 去斯卡裏夫了
He's there, sir. On Scarif.
那裏保存著太空站的原始設計圖嗎
The original plans for this station are kept there, are they not?
是的
They are.
準備跳入超空間
Prepare for the jump to hyperspace
馬上報告維達大人
and inform Lord Vader.
你需要幫忙嗎
Can we help you?
我覺得不必了
That won't be necessary.
議員
Senator!
報告議員
嗨 什麼事 列兵
Stop right there, Private.
讓他說
Let him speak.
我們截獲了帝國通訊 長官
Intercepted Imperial transmission, ma'am.
斯卡裏夫出現義軍
Rebels on Scarif.
我要見拉杜斯上將
I need to speak with Admiral Raddus.
他已返回船上
He's returned to his ship.
正要出發參戰
He's going to fight.
不
No!
全體機組人員注意
Attention, all flight personnel,
立即向你的指揮官報到
please report to your commanders immediately.
全體機組人員
All flight personnel,
立即向你的指揮官報到
please report to your commanders immediately.
目的地重新定為斯卡裏夫
We have been redirected to Scarif.
你們的領隊
Pilots, you'll be briefed
會在途中做出簡報
by your squadron leaders en route.
願原力與你們同在
May the Force be with you.
斯卡裏夫 他們要去斯卡裏夫嗎
Scarif? They're going to Scarif?
為什麼沒有人跟我說過這事呢 R2
Why does nobody ever tell me anything, R2?
快 快 我們走
Move, move, move!
前進 前進
Forward! Forward!
把他們引過來
Keep drawing them out!
12號平台需要增援
Pad 12, report to ground.
Coming in on our flank. We need numbers.
14平台 你那裏情況怎麼樣
Pad 14, what's going on down there?
回報狀態 所有平台立即報告
Status please. All pads report in immediately.
噢 不 到處都是叛軍
Oh, no. We have rebels everywhere!
我們接火了
We're taking fire!
12平台 14平台 請求支援
Pad 12, Pad 14 request assistance.
這是2號平台
This is Pad 2. Pad 2.
有40名叛軍從這兒向西移動
I spot 40 rebels heading west on Pad 2.
拿著它 說5號平台被叛軍壓制
Get on there. Tell him you're pinned down by rebels on Pad 5.
這裏是5號平台 我們守不住了 請支援
This is Pad 5! We're being overrun! Help us!
12 10 8 請確認
Pad 12, Pad 10, Pad 8, please confirm.
確認並回復
Confirm and report.
馬上向5號平台派出增援
Get reinforcements down to Pad 5 immediately!
這沒有反應 K
This is not working, K!
用右手
Right hand.
貝茲
Baze!
- 貝茲 - 什麼
- Baze! - What?
跑
Run!
卡拉巴斯特 AT-AT
Karabast! AT-AT!
快走
Move!
我是義軍聯盟拉杜斯上將
This is Admiral Raddus of the Rebel Alliance.
各中隊領隊報告情況
All squadron leaders, report in.
上將 這裏是藍色領隊 準備就緒
Admiral, this is Blue Leader standing by.
這裏是金色領隊 準備就緒
This is Gold Leader standing by.
我是紅色領隊 準備就緒
This is Red Leader standing by.
長官 發現叛軍飛船
Sir, those are rebel ships.
立刻聯絡戈林上將 快點去
Get Admiral Gorin, immediately!
總監 叛軍艦隊
Director, the rebel fleet,
目前正在護盾外集結
it's amassing outside the shield.
封鎖基地 全面封鎖
Lock down the base. Lock it down.
- 關閉護盾嗎 - 快去
- And close the shield? - Do it!
紅色 金色中隊 攻擊隊形
Red and Gold Squadrons, attack formations.
保衛艦隊
Defend the fleet.
藍色中隊 搶在閘門關閉前
Blue Squadron, get to the surface
強行通過
before they close that gate.
收到 上將
Copy you, Admiral.
藍色中隊 跟我來
Blue Squadron, on me!
收到 藍色領隊
Copy, Blue Leader.
得抓緊時間
We won't have long.
快關閉護盾閘口 快關閉
Close the field aperture now! Close it!
快點兒 快點兒 快點兒
Come on, come on, come on!
拉起來
Pull up!
義軍的艦隊抵達了
The rebel fleet has arrived.
什麼
What?
那邊還在戰鬥
There's fighting on the beach.
他們已經封鎖基地
They've locked down the base.
護盾閘門關閉了
They've closed the shield gate.
這意味著什麼
What does that mean?
被困住了嗎
We're trapped?
我們可以把設計圖發往義軍艦隊
We could transmit the plans to the rebel fleet.
我們得設法通知他們準備接收
We'd have to get a signal up to tell them it's coming.
可問題是這份數據文件太大
It's the size of the data files. That's the problem.
無法傳輸過去
They'll never get through.
必須想辦法先破壞護盾閘門
Someone has to take that shield gate down.
菩提 你能聽到嗎 菩提
Bodhi. Bodhi, can you hear me?
告訴我你還在
Bodhi, tell me you're out there.
菩提
Bodhi?
我在呢
I'm here.
等待指示
I was standing by.
他們開戰了 基地被封鎖了
They've started fighting. The base is on lockdown.
我知道 聽我說 義軍艦隊已經來了
I know. Listen to me. The rebel fleet is up there.
你讓他們在護盾閘門上炸個洞
You've gotta tell them to blow a hole in the shield gate...
我們好把設計圖發過去
so we can transmit the plans.
等等 我沒法 我沒有 沒有連上通訊塔
Wait. I can't. I'm not hooked into the comms tower.
我 我們沒 沒有連線過去
We're not tied in.
只有這個方法我們才能把圖傳出去
It's the only way we're getting them out of here.
快想辦法
Find a way!
掩護我們後方
Cover our backs.
你會用到它的
You'll need this.
你不是想要這個嗎
You wanted one, right?
琴 你的行為 總是這麼讓人 意想不到
Your behavior, Jyn Erso, is continually unexpected.
琴 快來
Jyn. Come on.
薩卡拉
Sa'kalla!
聽我下令開火
Fire on my command.
快看
Look!
準備一下 我們得出去一趟
Get ready. We're gonna have to go out there.
你要幹什麼
What are you doing?
他們關閉了護盾閘門
They've closed the shield gate.
我們困在這兒了
We're stuck here.
但是 義軍艦隊過來了
But the rebel fleet are pulling in.
我們需要找個足夠強的信號
We just have to get a signal strong enough to get through to them...
好通知他們我們被困在這裏了
and let them know that we're trapped down here.
為此 我們必須跟通訊塔連上
For that, we have to connect to the communications tower.
我在這邊接入平台線路
Now, I can patch us in over here, the landing pad.
但是你 必須去無線電那兒
But you have to get on the radio.
領幾個人去找到主控開關
Get one of the guys out there to find a master switch.
讓他們激活我們與通訊塔的連接
Get them to activate the connection between us and that comms tower.
明白了
Okay?
快去呀
Then go!
下面情況怎麼樣 上尉
What's going on down there, Lieutenant?
未知 長官
Unknown, sir.
聯絡不到他們
We can't raise them.
所有義軍頻道都被屏蔽了
All rebel frequencies are blocked.
繼續聯絡 攻擊那些殲星艦
Keep trying. Engage those Star Destroyers
同時開始探測那個護盾
and let's start probing that shield!
遵命 長官
Yes, sir!
開始攻擊
We're going in.
都跟緊我
Stay with me.
線路圖庫 二號數據塔
Schematic bank, data tower two.
我怎麼找到它
How do I find that?
搜索中
Searching.
我能定位磁帶位置
I can locate the tape,
但你必須使用把手抽取檔案
but you'll need to use the handles for extraction.
這東西到底是怎麼用的
What am I supposed to do with this?
總算找到了
Well, finally.
等等 停下
Wait! Stop!
叛軍 他們往那邊跑了
The rebels, they went over there.
K 你那兒有什麼情況
K, what's going on out there?
那裏有一個
There's one.
噢 好吧
Ah, well.
來呀
Come on!
紅色領隊 我是金色領隊
Red Leader, this is Gold Leader.
我們已展開對護盾閘門的攻擊
We're starting our attack run on the shield gate.
收緊編隊 小心那些炮塔
Keep it tight, and watch out for those towers.
敵機增多 在65重新編隊
More fighters. Form out at six-five.
長官 發現有敵機來襲
Sir, enemy fighters coming in.
梅爾西 梅爾西 請回話 你在嗎
Melshi! Melshi, come in. Are you there?
菩提和那邊發射信號 他已接入平台
Bodhi sent a signal from here. He's patching us in.
你們必須開啟到通訊塔的線路
But you guys have to open up a line for the tower.
怎麼接 請指示
How? Please advise.
在通訊塔底部有一個主開關
There's a master switch at the base of the comm tower.
主開關 長什麼樣 我們要找到什麼
Master switch? Describe. What are we looking for?
主開關什麼樣 位置在哪兒 快告訴我
What does it look like? The master switch? Where is it?
U翼 前去支援海灘部隊
U-wings, reinforce those troops on the beach.
全體士兵 跟我上
All fighters, on me.
我們必須清除空中威脅
We have to shield them from air attack.
所有增援部隊 朝這兒出發
Troop reinforcements. Here we go.
為了傑達
For Jedha!
對護盾的攻擊沒有效果
We're having no effect on that shield.
要多少火力才能打掉
How much more can that thing take?
跟緊我 紅色五號 你要去哪兒
Stick close, Red Five. Where are you goin'?
我被咬住了 我嘗試甩掉它們
They're all over me. I'm trying to lose them!
我是紅色五號 需要支援
This is Red Five! I need help!
超空間追蹤 怎麼打開導航系統
"Hyperspace tracking. Navigational systems."
往下兩個屏幕
Two screens down.
結構工程 打開那個
"Structural engineering." Open that one.
我被敵機咬住了
I've got one on my tail!
我來了
I'm on him!
項目代號名稱
Project code names:
平流層 馬克·奧米茄 帕克斯·歐若拉
"Stellarsphere, Mark Omega, Pax Aurora."
戰人之爪 折視棱鏡處 黑劍
"War-Mantle, Cluster Prism, Blacksaber."
怎麼了
What?
就是它
"Stardust."
星塵
That's it.
你怎麼知道
How do you know that?
因為那是我的名字
I know because it's me.
嗨 你 你是幹什麼的
Hey, you! Identify yourself.
我是
I can...
炮火來襲 隱蔽
Incoming fire! Get cover!
K 我們需要星塵計劃的文件
K, we need the file for Stardust.
星塵文件
Stardust.
就是它
That's it.
K
K?
快爬
Climb.
往上爬
你們還可以把設計圖發給艦隊
You can still send the plans to the fleet.
如果他們打開護盾閘門
If they open the shield gate...
你們可以從塔裏傳輸
you can broadcast from the tower.
現在開始關閉庫門
Locking the vault door now.
K
K?
K!
- 再見 - K
- Goodbye. - K!
長官 有人擅自進入了數據庫
Sir, unauthorized access at the data vault.
什麼
What?
剛剛發現的 長官
It's just come in, sir.
把我的衛隊派去參戰
Send my guard squadron into battle.
你們兩個跟我來 快
Two men with me, now.
把海灘給我立刻奪回來
Get that beach under control!
菩提 你在嗎 呼叫艦隊了嗎
Bodhi, are you there? Did you call the fleet?
我沒法回到船上
I can't get to the shuttle.
就沒法接通
I can't plug in.
必須接通 他們會攻擊閘門
You have to. They have to hit that gate.
只有護盾打開了 我們才能發送設計圖
If the shield's open, we can send the plans.
將軍 小心背後
General, behind you!
退後
Step back.
我們要墜機了
We're going down!
來啊
Come on!
梅爾西 梅爾西
Melshi, Melshi.
請講話
Come in, please.
我這頭已經接通
I'm tied in at my end.
我需要你打開線路
I just need an open line.
等一下
Hang on.
線路的主開關
The master switch.
就在控制台的旁邊
It's over near that console.
我來了
I'm going!
我拿到了
I've got it!
小心
Careful!
你沒事吧
You okay?
琴
Jyn!
原力與我同在 我與原力同在
I'm one with the Force, the Force is with me.
奇魯
Chirrut!
原力與我同在 我與原力同在
I'm one with the Force and the Force is with me.
I'm one with the Force, the Force is with me.
原力與我同在 我與原力同在
I'm one with the Force...
the Force is with me. I'm one with the Force...
原力與我同在
and the Force is with me.
原力與我同在 我與原力同在
I'm one with the Force, and the Force is with me.
奇魯 回來
Chirrut! Come back!
原力與我同在
I'm one with the Force...
通了
Yes!
上啊 快點上啊
Keep going! Keep going!
卡西安
Cassian!
奇魯 快回來 快回來
Chirrut! Come! Come with me!
奇魯
Chirrut!
Chirrut.
別死 別死
Don't go. Don't go.
我在這兒 我在這兒
I'm here, I'm here.
沒關係
It's okay.
我沒事 找到原力
It's okay. Look for the Force.
奇魯
Chirrut.
你就會找到我
And you will always find me.
原力與我同在 我跟原力也同在
The Force is with me and I'm one with the Force.
偏導護盾剩餘只有50%了 我們現在受損嚴重
Deflector shields down to 50%! We're sustaining heavy damage!
現在沒有回頭路了
There's no turning back now!
我們必須繼續進攻
We have to press the attack!
攻擊突破口
Hit that opening!
看到了 金色領隊
We see it, Gold Leader.
離子魚雷發射
Ion torpedoes away!
怎麼回事
What's happening?
引擎喪失動力了 長官
We've lost engine power, sir.
那艘殲星艦失去戰鬥力了
That Star Destroyer's disabled.
俠盜一號呼叫同盟艦隊 能聽到嗎
This is Rogue One calling any Alliance ships that can hear me.
我是俠盜一號 有人聽到嗎
Is there anybody out there? This is Rogue One.
請回話
Come in, over!
我是拉杜斯上將 俠盜一號 我們聽到了
This is Admiral Raddus, Rogue One. We hear you.
我拿到設計圖了
We have the plans.
死星設計圖找到了
They found the Death Star plans.
他們要用通訊塔傳送設計圖
They have to transmit them from the communications tower.
你們必須毀掉護盾閘門
You have to take down the shield gate.
他們才能發出信號
It's the only way they're gonna get them through.
調一艘錘頭輕護衛艦 我有辦法了
Call up a Hammerhead corvette. I have an idea.
俠盜一號待命 我們來了
Stand by, Rogue One. We're on it.
為你報仇 蓋倫
This is for you, Galen.
原力與我同在 我跟原力同在
The Force is with me, and I'm one with the Force.
五號輕護衛艦 鎖定目標
Corvette Five, locked on target!
準備撞擊
Prepare for impact.
亞光速推進器 推到全速
Sublight thrusters, full power!
重新校準天線
Reset antenna alignment.
反推引擎 全速
Reverse engines! Full power!
天線已校準
Antenna aligned.
開始準備傳輸
Ready to transmit.
你是誰
Who are you?
你知道我是誰
You know who I am.
我是琴·厄索
I'm Jyn Erso.
蓋倫和麗拉的女兒
Daughter of Galen and Lyra.
你輸了
You've lost.
噢 是嗎 輸在哪兒
Oh, I have, have I?
我替父親報仇了
My father's revenge.
他為死星設計了一個弱點
He built a flaw in the Death Star.
在核心放了一根導火索
He put a fuse in the middle of your machine...
現在全銀河系都知道怎麼點燃它
and I've just told the entire galaxy how to light it.
護盾還在運行著
The shield is up.
叛軍基地永遠收不到你的信號
Your signal will never reach the rebel base.
叛軍艦隊會全軍覆滅
All your ships in the air will be destroyed.
我損失的只是一點時間
I lose nothing but time.
而你 你和你的同夥
You, on the other hand...
搭上的卻是性命
die with the Rebellion.
正在傳輸
Transmitting.
上將 正在接收從斯卡裏夫來的數據
Admiral, receiving transmission from Scarif.
別去 別去
Leave it, leave it!
夠了
That's it.
走吧
Let's go.
數據接收完畢
Transmission received.
將軍 拿到設計圖了
Admiral, we have the plans!
她成功了
She did it!
你覺得會有人在聽嗎
Do you think anybody's listening?
有人聽
I do.
一定會有人聽
Someone's out there.
長官 一個巨型物體
Sir, we're detecting a massive object
正在脫離超空間軌道
emerging from hyperspace.
長官 要瞄準他們的艦隊嗎
Sir, shall I begin targeting their fleet?
維達大人會對付它
Lord Vader will handle the fleet.
瞄準斯卡裏夫基地 單反應堆點火
Target the base at Scarif, single reactor ignition.
遵命
Yes, sir.
我們走
Come on.
準備好了就發射
You may fire when ready.
啟動主點火程序
Commence primary ignition.
俠盜一號 願原力與你們同在
Rogue One, may the Force be with you.
所有飛船做好準備 跳入超空間
All ships prepare for jump to hyperspace.
你父親會為你感到驕傲的 琴
Your father would have been proud of you, Jyn.
叛軍旗艦已失去戰鬥力 大人
The rebel flagship is disabled, my lord...
但他們收到了地面發送的信息
but has received transmissions from the surface.
準備登艦部隊
Prepare a boarding party.
遵命 大人
Yes, my lord.
快點兒
Hurry!
快走 我們要立即撤退
Let's go! We gotta go, now!
快 快 快
Move! Move! Move!
快點兒 快走
Hurry. Let's go!
快
Let's go!
卡住了
It's stuck!
嗨
Hey!
幫幫我們
Hey! Help!
全體開火
Open fire!
救救我們
Help us!
卡住了
It's jammed!
用力
Pull it!
拿去 拿著
Here! Here!
快拿走 快
Take it! Take it!
快走
Launch!
確保氣閘門完全封閉
Make sure you secure the airlock.
準備發射逃生艙
And prepare the escape pods.
殿下
Your highness.
我們收到的信息
The transmission we received.
是什麼內容
What is it they've sent us?
希望
Hope.
翻譯 林野
翻譯 姚望
故事  約翰·諾爾  加裏·威塔
原著創意作者  喬治·盧卡斯
製片人  凱瑟琳·肯尼迪  愛麗森·希阿莫  西蒙·艾曼紐爾
執行製片人  約翰·諾爾  傑森·麥克蓋特林
攝影指導  格雷格·弗萊瑟
藝術指導  江道格  尼爾·拉蒙特
剪輯  約翰·吉爾瑞  傑貝茲·奧爾森  科林·高爾迪
音樂  邁克·吉亞奇諾
星球大戰原創音樂  約翰·威廉姆斯
服裝設計  格林·狄龍  達夫·克羅斯曼
聯合製片人  約翰·斯沃茲  蘇珊·陶納  凱利·哈特
視覺特效總監  約翰·諾爾  摩恩·裏奧
生物特效化妝  尼爾·斯坎倫
視覺特效製片人  珍妮特·勒文  艾琳·迪塞爾特
選角導演  吉娜·傑
菲麗希緹·瓊斯
迭戈·魯納
本·門德爾森
甄子丹
麥斯·米科爾森
艾倫·圖代克
裏茲·阿邁德
吉米·史密斯
詹姆斯·厄爾·瓊斯  黑武士達斯·維達配音
以及  姜文
以及  福裏斯特·惠特克
盧卡斯電影公司  榮譽出品
加裏斯·愛德華斯  作品
無聊老生    誠意製作